<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Applications</title>
  <body>

<h1>Application ideas</h1>

<ul>
<li>
<B>Audio mixing environment:</B>
<a href="&site;/data/images/apps/ideas/mixer.png">
<img align="right" alt="mixer diagram"
     src="&site;/data/images/apps/ideas/mixer-small.png"/></a>
<p>
Complex audio environments require a high degree of repluggability.  
This is usually done with racks of equipment and lots of cables, with a 
patch panel if you're lucky.  Instead, GStreamer gives you unlimited 
access to &quot;hardware&quot;, within the constraints of your CPU.</p>

<p>With access to <a href="http://www.ladspa.org">LADSPA</a> plugins and
multi-channel sound hardware via the ALSA source and
sink, complex processing is as easy as drawing your idea mixing system in
the editor.</p>

<p>Of course, just having the processing half isn't enough, which is why
significant time and effort will need to be expended in the user interface
and automation systems.</p>
</li>

<li><b>DVD player:</b>
<p>A DVD player is a relatively easy thing to construct given the right 
components, some of which already exist.  A simple DVD player would look 
something like this (as much as ASCII graphs look like anything):</p>

<pre>
                                           |=thread===========|
                      -------(audio)-------|ac3dec--audiosink |
|=thread============|/                     |==================|
| dvdsrc--mpeg2parse|         |=thread============================|
|===================|-(video)-|mpeg2dec--  |=bin================| |
                    \         |========| \-|subtitle--videosink | |
                     \---(subtitle)----|---|====================| |
                                       |==========================|
</pre>

<p><a href="gst-player/">gst-player</a> should be 
capable of constructing the above graph without any outside assistance.  
Further work is necessary for the system to be capable of navigation, 
menus, and angles.  Most such components would live outside the pipeline 
in the DVD player application, but one might conceive of a case where 
those pieces of code are capable of being autoplugged, reducing the act of 
watching a DVD to the following command:</p>

<pre>
gst-player /dev/dvd
</pre>
</li>

<li><I><B>Your application here!</B></I></li>
</ul>


  </body>
</page>
