<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Applications</title>
  <body>

  <p>
 Because GStreamer is designed to be as generic as possible, a wide 
 range of applications can be build on top of it with very little effort, 
 allowing the programmer to focus on the user interface and human interaction
 components of application design.
</p>

<!--
<h1>Applications using GStreamer</h1>

<p>
 We've started a <a href="../status/?category=2">status page</a> that tracks the 
 progress of applications that written using GStreamer. There are some really nice applications out there using Gstreamer now so be sure to check it out. And of course, let us know if you have anything you'd like to add to it.
</p>
-->

<h1>GStreamer applications</h1>
<p>All applications listed alphabetically</p>

<h2>acast</h2>
<p><a href="http://zaheer.merali.org/mediawiki/index.php/Acast">acast</a> is a program for webcasting audio from your sound device to a variety of different streaming servers and has GTK+2 and console interfaces.
</p>

<h2>amaroK</h2>
<p><a href="http://amarok.kde.org/">amaroK</a> is an audio player for KDE.</p>

<h2>Banshee</h2>
<p><a href="http://sonance.aaronbock.net/">Banshee</a> is a music player for GNOME using Mono</p>

<h2>Buzztard</h2>
<p><a href="http://buzztard.org/index.php/Overview">Buzztard</a> is music application similar to Buzz or FastTracker.</p>

<h2>Cupid</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://ronald.bitfreak.net/cupid.php">A GStreamer video Recorder</a>,
which is currently under development and will be able to record perfectly synchronized audio/video
in any format supported by GStreamer.</p>

<h2>The Dave/Dina Project</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.davedina.org/content/">The Dave/Dina Project</a> is a set-top box distribution for playing and recording TV and multimedia and much more.</p>

<h2>Eina</h2>
<p><a href="http://bolgo.cent.uji.es/proyectos/eina-en">Eina</a> is a traditional audio player with a GTK2 interface.</p>

<h2>Flumotion</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.fluendo.com">Flumotion</a> is a distributed streaming media server</p>

<h2>Gamp</h2>
<p><a href="http://gamp.sourceforge.net/">Gamp</a> is a GNOME based media player</p>

<h2>GNOME Media</h2>
<p><a href="http://ronald.bitfreak.net/gnome-media.php">GNOME Media</a> uses GStreamer for the volume control, sound recorder and cd player.</p>

<h2>Goobox</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.gnomefiles.org/app.php?soft_id=531">Goobox</a> is a GNOME based cd-player and ripper</p>

<h2>GStreamer Editor</h2>
<p>A graphical pipeline contruction interface called
<a href="&site;/modules/gst-editor.html">GStreamer Editor</a>.</p>

<h2>Jamboree</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.imendio.com/projects/jamboree/">Jamboree</a> is a GNOME based music player developed by Imendio.</p>

<h2>JuK</h2>
<p><a href="http://developer.kde.org/~wheeler/juk.html">JuK</a> is an audio jukebox for KDE.</p>

<h2>Kaffeine</h2>
<p><a href="http://kaffeine.sourceforge.net/">Kaffeine</a> is a KDE based media player</p>

<h2>Lindele</h2>
<p><a href="http://projects.subpop.net/lindele/">Lindele</a> is a GNOME based music player</p>

<h2>Marlin</h2>
<p><a href="http://marlin.sourceforge.net/">marlin</a> is a sample editor for Gnome.</p>

<h2>Monkey Bubble</h2>
<p><a href="http://home.gna.org/monkeybubble/">Monkey Bubble</a> a fun and cool game for GNOME using GStreamer to play some funky music and sweet sound effects.</p>


<h2>Muine</h2>
<p><a href="http://muine.gooeylinux.org/">Muine</a> is a music player for GNOME using the Mono framework.</p>

<h2>Navys</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.navsys.org">Navsys</a> is a GPS map application and music player in one. Music player is using GStreamer.</p>

<h2>Pakt</h2>
<p><a href="http://subsignal.org/pakt/">Pakt</a> is a XML abstraction for GObjects used 
with GStreamer to monitor and change elements parameters and pipeline structures.</p>

<h2>Permovi</h2>
<p><a href="http://forge.novell.com/modules/xfmod/project/?permovi">Permovi</a> 
is a Linux-based HTPC (Home Theatre PC) application. It transforms a PC into a standalone CD-player/tuner/DVD-player/PVR device. Permovi is using the Mono framework.
</p>

<h2>Pitivi</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.pitivi.org/">Pitivi</a>
is a Non-Linear video editor utilizing the power of GStreamer and the Gnonlin non-linear video editing library.
</p>

<h2>Player</h2>
<p><a href="http://linux-media.net/player/">Player</a>
is a simple to use player which features inline visualizations.
</p>

<h2>Rhythmbox</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.rhythmbox.org/">Rhythmbox</a> is an integrated music management application, originally inspired by Apple's iTunes.
</p>

<h2>Siren</h2>
<p><a href="http://jodrell.net/projects/siren">Siren</a> lightweight GTK2 music
player written in Perl.</p>

<h2>Sound Converter</h2>
<p><a href="http://soundconverter.berlios.de/">Sound Converter</a> Small GNOME based sound conversion application.</p>

<h2>Sound Juicer</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">Sound Juicer</a> is a clean, mean, and lean CD ripper for GNOME.</p>

<h2>SoundScrape</h2>
<p><a href="http://ambient.2y.net/soundscrape/">SoundScrape</a> is a modular audio synthesizer with built in GUILE scriptability.</p>

<h2>Thoggen</h2>
<p><a href="http://thoggen.net/">Thoggen</a> is a DVD backup utility using GStreamer with a nice GTK+ frontend. Powerfull and easy to use.
</p>

<h2>Totem</h2>
<p><a href="http://hadess.net/totem.php3">Totem</a> is a movie player for the GNOME desktop.
</p>

<h2>Towel</h2>
<p><a href="http://towel.sourceforge.net/">Towel</a> is a GTKMM based music player.</p>

<h2>Video-Whale</h2>
<p><a href="videowhale.html">Video-Whale</a> is an implementation of a Gstreamer-based video-wall. Making a video wall with GStreamer is easy, this article with pictures from Zeeshan Ali shows you how.
</p>

<h2>WaveMixer</h2>
<p><a href="http://wavemixer.sourceforge.net/">WaveMixer</a> is a multitrack sound editor written with gtkmm and GStreamer.</p>

<h2>Wechselspieler</h2> 
<p><a href="http://wechselspieler.sourceforge.net/">Wechselspieler</a> is an 
artistic tool for mapping movements in video to MIDI events</p>

<h1>Experimental GStreamer applications</h1>

<h2>Aldegonde</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://ronald.bitfreak.net/aldegonde.php">Aldegonde</a> is a 
simple media player made to ease debugging of GStreamer playback issues. 
</p>

<h2>Kiss</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://ronald.bitfreak.net/kiss.php">Kiss</a> is a simple KDE base media player meant as an example application for KDE developers who want to use GStreamer.
</p>

<h2>gst-sci</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.schleef.org/">gst-sci</a> are a collection of scientific plugins for GStreamer.</p>

<h1>Application ideas</h1>
<p>
Just about anything you can think to do with media is possible with
GStreamer.
You can <A href="ideas.html">see some of our ideas for applications</A>.
If you're not sure if your idea would work, just hop on the <A
HREF="http://lists.sourceforge.net/mailman/listinfo/gstreamer-devel">gstreamer-devel</A>
mailing list and ask us, we'll be glad to discuss it with you!</p>

  </body>
</page>
