<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Applications</title>
  <body>


<h1>GStreamer applications</h1>
<p>
 Because GStreamer is designed to be as generic as possible, a wide 
 range of applications can be built on top of it with very little effort,
 allowing the programmer to focus on the user interface and human interaction
 components of application design.
</p>
<p>All applications listed alphabetically</p>

<h2>amaroK</h2>
<p><a href="http://amarok.kde.org/">amaroK</a> is an audio player for KDE.</p>



<h2>Advene</h2>
<p><a href="http://liris.cnrs.fr/advene/">Advene</a>
(Annotate Digital Video, Exchange on the NEt) aims at providing a model and
a format to share annotations about digital video documents (movies, courses,
conferences...), as well as tools to edit and visualize the hypervideos
generated from both the annotations and the audiovisual documents.</p>

<h2>Arista</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.transcoder.org/">Arista Transcoder</a> is an easy to
use transcoder application.</p>

<h2>Audition</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.rillion.net/audition/index.html">Audition</a>
Audition is an ncurses-based audio player for the console.</p>

<h2>Banshee</h2>
<p><a href="http://banshee-project.org/Main_Page">Banshee</a> is a music player for GNOME using Mono</p>
	
<h2>Buzztard</h2>
<p><a href="http://buzztard.org/index.php/Overview">Buzztard</a> is music application similar to Buzz or FastTracker.</p>

<h2>AirTime&amp;CampCaster</h2>
<p><a href="http://code.sourcefabric.org/projects">AirTime&amp;CampCaster</a> is radio management software that provides live studio broadcast capabilities as well as remote automation in one integrated system.</p>

<h2>dmapd</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.flyn.org/projects/dmapd/">dmapd</a> is a media server that implements
Apple's DAAP and DPAP protocols. Dmapd can share content with Apple iTunes,
Apple iPhoto, Roku's SoundBridge products, Rhythmbox, etc. dmapd uses GStreamer
to read media metadata and perform real-time transcoding of audio formats</p>


<h2>Eina</h2>
<p><a href="http://eina.sourceforge.net/">Eina</a> is a traditional audio player with a GTK2 interface.</p>

<h2>Empathy</h2>
<p><a href="https://live.gnome.org/Empathy">Empathy</a> is a messaging client with
 VoIP and Video conferencing support.</p>

<h2>Flumotion</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.fluendo.com">Flumotion</a> is a distributed streaming media server.</p>

<h2>Freemix</h2>
<p><a href="http://freemix.forja.rediris.es/">Fremix</a> is a live video performance application.</p>

<h2>Gamp</h2>
<p><a href="http://gamp.sourceforge.net/">Gamp</a> is a GNOME based media player.</p>

<h2>Geekcast</h2>
<p><a href="http://home.gna.org/geekast/">Geekast</a> is a GNOME P2P streaming client writen in Ruby.</p>

<h2>GEntrans</h2>
<p><a href="http://gentrans.sourceforge.net/">GEntrans</a> provides a gst-python based command-line transcoding application,
as well as various GStreamer filter elements ported from other sources.
In particular, it can serve as an enhanced gst-launch alternative.</p>

<h2>Gnash</h2>
<p><a href="http://gnashdev.org/">Gnash</a> is the GNU Flash movie player, which can be run standalone on the desktop or an embedded device, as well as as a plugin for several browsers.</p>

<h2>GNOME DVB Daemon</h2>
<p><a href="https://live.gnome.org/DVBDaemon">DVBDaemon</a> is a daemon that lets you watch 
DVB streams and check out the EPG.</p>

<h2>GNOME Subtitles</h2>
<p><a href="http://gnome-subtitles.sourceforge.net">GNOME Subtitles</a>
is a subtitle editor for the GNOME desktop. It supports the most common
text-based subtitle formats and allows for subtitle editing, translation and
synchronization.  It uses GStreamer for the video playback.
</p>

<h2>GMediaRender</h2>
<p><a href="http://gmrender.nongnu.org/">GMediaRender</a> is a upnp client for 
use with upnp media servers</p>

<h2>GstLAL</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.lsc-group.phys.uwm.edu/daswg/projects/gstlal.html">GstLAL</a> is a
suite of gstreamer elements and applications for gravitational wave data analysis.</p>

<h2>Istanbul</h2>
<p><a href="http://live.gnome.org/Istanbul">Istanbul</a> is a screen recorder
</p>

<h2>Jokosher</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.jokosher.org/">Jokosher</a> is a multitrack music editor
</p>

<h2>JuK</h2>
<p><a href="http://developer.kde.org/~wheeler/juk.html">JuK</a> is an audio jukebox for KDE.</p>

<h2>Kaffeine</h2>
<p><a href="http://kaffeine.sourceforge.net/">Kaffeine</a> is a KDE based media player.</p>

<h2>Landell</h2>
<p><a href="http://landell.holoscopio.com/">Landell</a> is an audio and video streaming server.</p>.

<h2>Listen</h2>
<p><a href="http://listengnome.free.fr/">Listen</a> is a GNOME music player written in Python</p>

<h2>LongoMatch</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.ylatuya.es">LongoMatch</a> is a cross-platform
sports video analysis tool based on Mono, Gtk+ and GStreamer.</p>

<h2>Marlin</h2>
<p><a href="http://marlin.sourceforge.net/">marlin</a> is a sample editor for Gnome.</p>

<h2>Minirok</h2>
<p><a href="http://chistera.yi.org/~adeodato/code/minirok/">Minirok</a> is a small music player for KDE/Qt.</p>


<h2>Monkey Bubble</h2>
<p><a href="http://home.gna.org/monkeybubble/">Monkey Bubble</a> a fun and cool game for GNOME using GStreamer to play some funky music and sweet sound effects.</p>

<h2>Movi</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.tandberg.com/products/pc-video-conferencing.jsp">TANDBERG Movi</a> is a professional video conferencing system, supporting HD video and Echo Cancellation.</p>

<h2>Muine</h2>
<p><a href="http://muine.gooeylinux.org/">Muine</a> is a music player for GNOME using the Mono framework.</p>

<h2>OggConvert</h2>
<p><a href="http://oggconvert.tristanb.net">OggConvert</a> is a tool for converting video to Ogg,Theora,Dirac and Vorbis formats.</p>

<h2>Pakt</h2>
<p><a href="http://subsignal.org/pakt/">Pakt</a> is a XML abstraction for GObjects used 
with GStreamer to monitor and change elements parameters and pipeline structures.</p>

<h2>Parole</h2>
<p><a href="http://goodies.xfce.org/projects/applications/parole">Parole</a> is a video player made
to integrate well with the XFCE desktop.</p>

<h2>Pitivi</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.pitivi.org/">Pitivi</a>
is a Non-Linear video editor utilizing the power of GStreamer and the Gnonlin non-linear video editing library.
</p>

<h2>Quod Libet</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.sacredchao.net/quodlibet">Quod Libet</a> is a Music Manager for GNOME written in Python</p>

<h2>Quotidian</h2>
<p><a href="http://quotid.com/">Quotidian</a> is a 3-d browser for time and events and runs on Linux, Windows and Mac</p>

<h2>Rhythmbox</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.rhythmbox.org/">Rhythmbox</a> is an integrated music management application, originally inspired by Apple's iTunes.
</p>

<h2>Rygel</h2>
<p><a href="https://live.gnome.org/Rygel">Rygel</a> is a DLNA streaming server and renderer.</p>

<h2>Scenic</h2>
<p><a href="http://scenic.sat.qc.ca/">Scenic</a> is a web-based telepresence application for venues and live performance. It is part of the PropulseART  project. Scenic's features include remote operation, multi-channel audio and serial transmission.</p>

<h2>Songbird</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.songbirdnest.com/">Songbird</a> is a cross-platform media player written using the XUL toolkit from Mozilla.</p>
<h2>Sound Converter</h2>

<p><a href="http://soundconverter.org/">Sound Converter</a> Small GNOME based sound conversion application.</p>

<h2>Sound Juicer</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">Sound Juicer</a> is a clean, mean, and lean CD ripper for GNOME.</p>

<h2>Togra</h2>
<p><a href="http://togra.sourceforge.net/">Togra</a> is a 3D multimedia framework</p>

<h2>Thoggen</h2>
<p><a href="http://thoggen.net/">Thoggen</a> is a DVD backup utility using GStreamer with a nice GTK+ frontend. Powerfull and easy to use.
</p>

<h2>Totem</h2>
<p><a href="http://projects.gnome.org/totem/">Totem</a> is a movie player for the GNOME desktop.
</p>

<h2>Towel</h2>
<p><a href="http://towel.sourceforge.net/">Towel</a> is a GTKMM based music player.</p>

<h2>Transmageddon</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.linuxrising.org">Transmageddon</a> is a GTK based Video and Audio Transcoder
and remuxer</p>

<h2>Wechselspieler</h2> 
<p><a href="http://wechselspieler.sourceforge.net/">Wechselspieler</a> is an 
artistic tool for mapping movements in video to MIDI events</p>

<h1>Experimental GStreamer applications</h1>

<h2>Permovi</h2>
<p><a href="http://forge.novell.com/modules/xfmod/project/?permovi">Permovi</a>
is a Linux-based HTPC (Home Theatre PC) application. It transforms a PC into a standalone CD-player/tuner/DVD-player/PVR device. Permovi is using the Mono framework.
</p>

<h2>Video-Whale</h2>
<p><a href="videowhale.html">Video-Whale</a> is an implementation of a Gstreamer-based video-wall. Making a video wall with GStreamer is easy, this article with pictures from Zeeshan Ali shows you how.
</p>

<h2>gst-sci</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.schleef.org/">gst-sci</a> are a collection of scientific plugins for GStreamer.</p>

<h1>Application ideas</h1>
<p>
Just about anything you can think to do with media is possible with
GStreamer.
You can <A href="ideas.html">see some of our ideas for applications</A>.
If you're not sure if your idea would work, just hop on the <A
HREF="http://lists.freedesktop.org/mailman/listinfo/gstreamer-devel">gstreamer-devel</A>
mailing list and ask us, we'll be glad to discuss it with you!</p>

  </body>
</page>
