<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
<head>
  <title>GStreamer Google Summer of Code: DASH WebM</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1>GStreamer Google Summer of Code: DASH WebM</h1>

<p>
<h1>Interested Mentors:</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Thiago Santos</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
<h1>Description:</h1>
</p>

<p>
Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH) is an adaptive bitrate streaming technique that enables high quality streaming of media content over the Internet delivered from conventional HTTP web servers.
It works by breaking the content into a sequence of small HTTP-based file segments, each segment containing a short interval of playback time of a content that is potentially many hours in duration, such as a movie or the live broadcast of a sports event.
The content is made available at a variety of different bit rates, i.e., alternative segments encoded at different bit rates covering aligned short intervals of play back time are made available.
As the content is played back by an MPEG-DASH client, the client automatically selects from the alternatives the next segment to download and play back based on current network conditions.
The client selects the segment with the highest bit rate possible that can be downloaded in time for play back without causing stalls or re-buffering events in the playback.
</p>

<p>
<quot>Implement a plugin to support WebM DASH streaming based on the existing MP4 DASH plugin.</quot>
</p>

<p>
Provide proper Opus/VP8/VP9 support in Matroska/WebM.
</p>

<p>
<h1>Required Skills:</h1>
<ul>
  <li>GStreamer Basics</li>
  <li>Understanding media formats</li>
  <li>Knowledge of HTTP Requests</li>
</ul>
</p>


<p>
<h1>Student Notes:</h1>
</p>

<p>
<h1>Related links:</h1>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://wiki.webmproject.org/adaptive-streaming/webm-dash-specification">http://wiki.webmproject.org/adaptive-streaming/webm-dash-specification</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=727305">https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=727305</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=729950">https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=729950</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MPEG_DASH">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MPEG_DASH</a></li>
</ul>
</p>

</body>
</page>
