<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
<head>
  <title>GStreamer Google Summer of Code: Static ORC</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1>GStreamer Google Summer of Code: Static Compilation for ORC</h1>

<p>
<quot>Compile assembly code generated by Orc at build time.</quot>
</p>

<p>
<h1>Interested Mentors:</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Sebastian Dröge, Wim Taymans, Luis de Bethencourt</li>
</ul>
</p>

<h1>Description</h1>
<p>
Orc is basically a simplified assembly language for data processing (no loops/jumps etc.),
it's supposed to map to SIMD instructions on various architectures curently there
are two things:
<ul>
  <li>liborc, which is a JIT compiler that will at run-time take orc code (in some byte
format) and generate machine code for the architecture in question on the fly and then
execute that whenever there's a function call</li>
  <li>we have C backup functions as .c files in the gstreamer source code, which are
also compiled in when orc can't compile some code (for various reasons), or liborc is
not available, then the C backup function will be used that's the current state of
things.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
Now, what one could also do is: use orcc at gstreamer build-time to compile assembly
source code, and then have the compiler/assembler use that instead of the C backup
function that's useful on e.g. iOS (where liborc can't generate code at runtime for
security reasons, memory must be executable) but could also be useful when you know
your target architecture, on embedded systems (then you don't need to link to liborc
and generate stuff at runtime, you just pre-generate the assembly for your target
arch and use that) so it involves some build system fiddling and making sure the
assembly output orc generates is good
</p>

<p>
<h1>Student Notes:</h1>
</p>

<p>
<h1>Related links:</h1>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://code.entropywave.com/orc/">http://code.entropywave.com/orc/</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/gstreamer/orc/">http://cgit.freedesktop.org/gstreamer/orc/</a></li>
</ul>
</p>

</body>
</page>
