<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2012</title>

  <body>
<table>
<tr><td>
<h1>GStreamer Conference 2012</h1>
<h2>August 27th and August 28th, 2012 · Sheraton San Diego Hotel &amp; Marina · San Diego, USA</h2>
<p>
We are back for a third year of the GStreamer Conference, and this year we are taking the GStreamer Conference to the United States and San Diego. This year we will be co-hosting with the LinuxCon North America, the Linux Plumbers Conference and the Linux Kernel Summit. The event will be held at the Sheraton San Diego Hotel and Marina.
</p>
<p>
<b>Call for Papers</b>
</p>
<p>
If you are interested in presenting at this years GStreamer Conference please send an abstract to <a href="mailto:christian.schaller@gmail.com">Christian Schaller</a> before the 25th of May 2012. We will be happy to accept talks on any subject relating to open source and multimedia. Last year in addition to talks about GStreamer we had presentations about Pulse Audio, VP8 and WebM and Xiph.org codecs for instance. 
</p>
</td>
<td valign="top">
<!--
<h1>Platinum Sponsor</h1>
<p>
<a href="http://www.collabora.com/projects/gstreamer/"><img src="sponsor_150x49_collabora.png" alt="Collabora" height="49" width="150" /></a>
</p>
<h2>Silver Sponsors</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://www.fluendo.com"><img src="sponsor_149x36_fluendo.png" alt="Fluendo" height="36" width="149" /></a>
</p>
<p>
<a href="http://www.google.com"><img src="sponsor_150x50_google.png" alt="Google" height="50" width="150" /></a>
</p>
-->
<h2>Special Media Partners</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://www.ubicast.eu/"><img src="sponsor_150x45_UbiCast.png" alt="Ubi Cast" height="45" width="150" /></a>
</p>
<p>
<small>
Interested in <a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference/2012/gstreamer-sponsor.pdf">becoming a sponsor?</a></small>
</p>
</td></tr>
</table>
<h2>Registration</h2>
<p>
We will have information for registrering online very soon.
</p>

<h2>Who Should Join?</h2>
<p>
Anyone interested in open source multimedia is encouraged to join us at the GStreamer Conference 2012.
If you are a hobbyist or a student interested in the field of multimedia, or working for a company
using or looking to use GStreamer in their products, then this is the perfect event for you to network
at and learn more about the latest technological breakthroughs in and around GStreamer. The talks 
will target both developers and managers alike.
</p>
<h2>Hotel</h2>
<p>
The GStreamer Conference is being held in San Diego, California from August 27 – August 28 in the Sheraton San Diego Hotel &amp; Marina.  GStreamer Conference attendees can avail themselves of rooms at a Linux Foundation discounted booking rate of US $170 a night (plus taxes) at this hotel. We encourage you to stay on-site to take full advantage of the conference.  Please note that rooms in our reserved block will include internet in guest rooms at no additional cost. Be aware that with LinuxCon running during the same days at the same hotel, rooms in this discounted block will go fast.
</p>
<p>
<pre>
Sheraton Hotel &amp; Marina
1380 Harbor Island Drive
San Diego, CA 92101
Tel: +1 619-291-2900
</pre>
</p>
<p>
To make your room reservation online, please <a href="https://www.starwoodmeeting.com/StarGroupsWeb/booking/reservation?id=1203149218&amp;key=8AF0A">click here</a>.  You may also call the Reservation Center to make a reservation at 1-877-734-2726 and ask for the LinuxCon room rate. 
</p>
<p>
<table>
<tr><td><img src="http://www.starwoodhotels.com/pub/media/127/she127ex.99865_md.jpg" width="343" height="230"/>
</td></tr>
<tr><td><b>Sheraton Hotel &amp; Marina</b></td></tr>
</table>
</p>
<p>If you have any questions about the GStreamer Conference please contact <a href="mailto:christian.schaller@gmail.com">Christian Schaller</a>.</p>
<p><i>If you want information on last years conference you will find that on the <a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference/2011">GStreamer Conference 2011</a> website.</i></p>
  </body>
</page>
