<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2010</title>
  <body>
<h1>GStreamer Conference 2010</h1>
<h2>Cambridge, United Kingdom 26th of October 2010</h2>
<p>
In conjuction with the <a href="http://www.embeddedlinuxconference.com/elc_europe10/">
CE Linux Conference Europe</a> we are happy to host and arrange the first full day conference
focusing on GStreamer and related technologies. Speakers from a wide range of companies and 
fields will attend to speak about available GStreamer technologies and future developments.
</p>
<p>
The conference will be held in the ballroom at the <a href="http://www.universityarms.info/">
University Arms Hotel</a> the day before the CE Linux Europe conference, making it ideal to combine 
the two events.
</p>
<p>
The talks hosted will cover a range of technologies built around GStreamer, both aimed at embedded,
desktop and server usage. There will also be a presentation on the plans for the GStreamer 1.0 release.
</p>
<h2>Technologies covered</h2>
<p>
We expect to have talks covering these topics and more, this site will be updated
with an actual agenda soon.
</p>

<ul>
<li>GStreamer 1.0</li>
<li>DLNA support</li>
<li>Cross platform development with GStreamer</li>
<li>Telepathy VOIP and videoconferencing</li>
<li>GStreamer and Android</li>
<li>GStreamer and MeeGo</li>
<li>GStreamer, Webkit and HTML5</li>
<li>Case studies on GStreamer product deployments</li>
</ul>

<h2>Call for papers</h2>
<p>
If you are interested in doing a presentation at the GStreamer Conference 2010 please send 
an abstract to christian.schaller(at)collabora.co.uk before June 30, 2010.
Speakers will be notified by July 15, 2010 
</p>
<h2>Registration</h2>
<p>
Registration for this event will be handled through the 
<a href="http://www.embeddedlinuxconference.com/elc_europe10/"> CE Linux Europe 2010 website</a>, 
please check back there for updates on when you can register.
</p>

<h2>Who Should Join?</h2>
<p>
Anyone interested in open source multimedia are encouraged to join us at the GStreamer Conference 2010.
If you are a hobbyist or a student interested in the field of multimedia or working for a company
using or looking to GStreamer on their products then this is the perfect event for you to network
and learn more about what is happening. The talks should be target both developers and
managers alike.
</p>
<p>
<table>
<tr><td><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1361/1330772310_39512c9610.jpg" width="500" height="375"/>
</td></tr>
<tr><td><b>Photo of Cambridge Arms Hotel</b></td></tr>
</p>

  </body>
</page>
