<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2011</title>
  <body>
<h1>GStreamer Conference 2011</h1>
<h2>October 24 - 25, 2011 · Clarion Congress Hotel · Prague, Czech Republic</h2>
<h2></h2>
<p>
After a successful launch last year in Cambridge, UK, we are very happy to invite everyone to the
second annual GStreamer Conference. This year we will be co-hosting with the <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linux-kernel-summit">
Linux Kernel Summit</a> and hold the event at the Clarion Congress Hotel in Prague, Czech Republic. Speakers from a wide range of companies and 
fields will attend to speak about available GStreamer technologies and future developments, including the release of GStreamer 1.0 which is scheduled
to happen not long after the conference.
</p>
<p>
The talks hosted will cover a range of technologies built around GStreamer aimed at embedded,
desktop and server usage. There will also be a presentation on the plans for the GStreamer 1.0 release.
</p>
<h2>Technologies covered</h2>
<p>
We have a long list of topics to be presented like:</p>

<ul>
<li>GStreamer 1.0</li>
<li>DLNA support</li>
<li>Cross platform development with GStreamer</li>
<li>Telepathy VOIP and videoconferencing</li>
<li>GStreamer and Android</li>
<li>GStreamer and MeeGo</li>
<li>GStreamer, Webkit and HTML5</li>
<li>Case studies on GStreamer product deployments</li>
</ul>
<h2>Registration</h2>
<p>
Registration is now open and you can take advantage of our early bird rebate by registring on <a href="http://www.regonline.com/Register/Checkin.aspx?EventID=977251">
the GStreamer 2011 registration page</a> provided by regonline and the Linux Foundation.
</p>
<h2>Call for Papers</h2>
<p>
We are not ready to accept submissions for talks at the GStreamer Conference 2011. Please send your abstract to 
<a href="mailto:christian.schaller@collabora.co.uk">Christian Schaller</a>. The deadline for talk submissions will be 1st of July
2011 and accepted talks will be notified before 15th of July 2011.
</p>
<h2>Sponsorship</h2>
<p>
We are working on a sponsorship structure for this years confererence. Will hope to announce details soon.
</p>
</p>
<h2>Who Should Join?</h2>
<p>
Anyone interested in open source multimedia is encouraged to join us at the GStreamer Conference 2011.
If you are a hobbyist or a student interested in the field of multimedia, or working for a company
using or looking to use GStreamer in their products, then this is the perfect event for you to network
at and learn more about the latest technological breakthroughs in and around GStreamer. The talks 
will target both developers and managers alike.
</p>
<p>Following on from the GStreamer Conference 2011 and the Linux Kernel Summit, at the same venue, is the <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/embedded-linux-conference-europe/">
Embedded Linux Conference Europe</a> and <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon-europe">LinuxCon Europe</a>, so combining these events with
the GStreamer Conference might be a good idea for many of our attendees.</p>
<h2>Hotel and Travel</h2>
<p>
The simplest option if you are attending it to book yourself a room at the <a href="http://www.cchp.cz/en/bookingconf/?price_group=32768&amp;hotel_id=2679&amp;service_model=2">
Clarion Congress Hotel Prague</a> as you would then be staying at the venue. If you use our link you will get our special conference rates at the hotel. There is
of course no requirement to stay at the hotel and you can of course use any lodging of your choosing and still attend the conference.
</p>
<p>
The closest airport is the Ruzyne International Airport and for those arriving by others means the conference center got a <a href="http://cchp.cz/en/about-us/#/2174&amp;2175">
page with directions for how to reach the Clarion Congress hotel</a>.</p>
<p>
<table>
<tr><td><img src="http://www.cchp.cz/image-cache/crop-524x300/448-exterier_298x168.png#?rounded&radius=10&color=FFFFFF" width="298" height="168"/>
</td></tr>
<tr><td><b>Clarion Congress Hotel, Prague</b></td></tr>
</table>
</p>
<p><i>If you want information on last years conference you will find that on the <a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference/2010">GStreamer Conference 2010</a> website.</i></p>
  </body>
</page>
