<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
    %site-entities;
    ]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2011 Program </title>

<body lang="en-US" dir="LTR">

<h1>Speakers bio and abstracts - GStreamer Conference 2011</h1>
<h2>October 24 - 25, 2011 · Clarion Congress Hotel · Prague, Czech Republic</h2>
<p><a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference">Back to conference main page</a></p>
<p><a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference/gstreamer-conference-timetable.html">Back to conference timetable</a></p>
<table width="100%" border="1" bordercolor="#C0C0C0" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="2">
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="taymans" id="taymans"></a>
	<p><b>Keynote - GStreamer 1.0, Wim Taymans, Collabora Multimedia</b></p>
	<p>
	Wim Taymans is one of the founders of the GStreamer project and the man behind the current GStreamer design. Wim has a long history in the development of multimedia software, starting with computer game development on the Commodore 64. Wim Taymans and is working on assisting Collabora customers with the design and use of GStreamer.
	</p>
	<p>
	Wim Taymans will in his keynote be speaking about the current state of GStreamer 1.0 development and highlight the most important changes in GStreamer 1.0 compared to the 0.10 release series.

	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="sauer" id="sauer"></a>
	<p><b>High complexity GStreamer pipelines, Stefan Sauer, Google</b></p>
	<p>Stefan is a software engineer working for Google on build infrastructure
tools. In the past he was working for Nokia on the multimedia stack used on their maemo internet tablets and phones. In his free time his is contributing to GStreamer, other GNOME projects (e.g. gtk-doc) and working on his music editor buzztard. He has a PhD in Human Computer Interaction from the Technical University of Dresden/Germany. Stefan now lives in Munich/Germany with his wife and his two kids.
	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="lundberg" id="lundberg"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer, Webkit and HTML5, Jonas Lundberg, Ericsson</b></p>
	<p>
	Jonas Lundberg is a senior researcher at Ericsson Research with over ten years of experience in multimedia research. His research interests include real-time multimedia services and web technologies. He has a master's degree in Computer Science from Luleå University of Technology, Sweden.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="quachio" id="quachio"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer and DASH, Emanuelle Quachio, ST</b></p>
	<p>Emanuele Quacchio received the Master Degree in Electronic Engineering from the Polytechnic of Turin, Italy, in 2003, and worked two year as a researcher in the Dept. of Electronics of the same University developing algorithms for image and video processing.
He joined STMicroelectronics at the System R&amp;D Division in 2006, where he is currently leading the design and management of projects on embedded multimedia applications, focusing on Internet media distribution and exploiting GStreamer media frameworks and other Open Source technologies. Since 2009 he is also coordinating the technical activities for STM in a number of EU funded projects.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="lespiau" id="lespiau"></a>
        <p><b>Media Explorer, Damien Lespiau, Intel</b></p>
	<p><b>Damien is a Software Engineer at Intel's Open Source Technology Center
working on the MeeGo Netbook project and on Media Explorer, an awesome
media player.  He maintains clutter-gst, the integration library for
Clutter and GStreamer and, in a past life, has been advocating GNOME
libraries and GStreamer in companies writing proprietary software.  In
his spare time he enjoys writing m4 macros and raising wombats.
	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="luther" id="luther"></a>
	<p><b>WebM and VP8 latest developments , John Luther, Google</b></p>
	<p>John Luther is Product Manager at the WebM Project. Prior to WebM, he was VP of Product Management at On2 Technologies, an early developer of video compression technology and creators of VP3, the codec that formed the basis for Ogg Theroa.</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="emont" id="emont"></a>
	<p><b>Time lapse and stabilising a sequence of images, Guillame Emont,  Igalia</b></p>
	<p>

	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="torra" id="torra"></a>
	<p><b>Timeshifting with GStreamer, Jossep Torra, Fluendo</b></p>
	<p>
	Josep Torra holds a Computer Engineering degree from the Open University of Catalonia (UOC), Catalonia, Spain. He joined Fluendo as senior developer and became a part of the codec development team for embedded systems in 2006. He currently works as a Technical Lead for the team developing codecs and multimedia related projects in a wide range of platforms, from desktop to embedded systems. Embedded Linux development, HW accelerated decoders, and performance optimization techniques are of special interest for Josep. He is also a developer on the GStreamer project.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="alaoui" id="alaoui"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer and Farsight, the easy way, Youness Alaoui,  Collabora</b></p>
	<p>
I'm a Software Developer working for Collabora for the past 4 years. I've worked mostly as a VoIP/Streaming expert on various technologies like GStreamer and Farsight. I'm the maintainer of libnice, a NAT-Traversal library implementing the ICE specification. In my free time, I'm the project leader of the aMSN Messenger client, as well as founder of the PSFreedom, PL3 and PS3MFW projects.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="sparell" id="sparell"></a>
	<p><b>Case Study- GStreamer at Oblong Industries, Carlton J. Sparell, Oblong Industries</b></p>
	<p>
Carlton leads product and video strategy at Oblong Industries.  He has more than twenty years experience designing systems relating to multi-modal interaction, distributed computing, streaming media, and interactive television.</p>
<p>
Prior to Oblong Industries, Carlton was VP Technology at Ucentric Systems, a pioneer in whole-home digital video recording and became Director Advanced Technologies for Motorola after Motorola’s acquisition of Ucentric in 2005.</p>
<p>
Carlton was a founder of Fantasma Networks, a silicon valley Ultra-Wide Band fabless semiconductor company and a Member of Research Staff at Paul Allen’s Interval Research Corporation in the mid to late 1990s.</p>
<p> 
Carlton holds a Master of Science from the MIT Media Laboratory and a Bachelor of Science from MIT in Electrical Science and Engineering.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="jaquez" id="jaquez"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer and SysLink, Victor Jaquez, Igalia</b></p>
	<p>
Víctor worked for TI, in Mexico, in the development of GStreamer elements for
the OMAP3 processors. At Igalia he has been involved in several projects for
OMAP3 and OMAP4 processors. He is now fooling around with the SysLink IPC
mechanism and its integration with GStreamer.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="muller" id="muller"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer 0.10 Status Report, Tim Muller, Collabora</b></p>
	<p>
Tim-Philipp Müller is a GStreamer developer and maintainer. He studied
in Hamburg, York and Aberystwyth before going to work for Fluendo. He
co-founded Collabora Multimedia in 2007 and currently lives in Bristol,
UK.</p>
	
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="pinochet" id="pinochet"></a>
	<p><b>Easy integration of GStreamer in Android, Reynaldo Pinochet</b></p>
	<p>
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr><td>
	<a name="schmidth" id="schmidth"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer and Blu-ray, Jan Schmidth, Oracle</b></p>
        <p>
Jan is a GStreamer maintainer and primary author of DVD playback
support, among other things. In the past he worked for Fluendo and Sun
Microsystems. Currently, he lives in Albury Australia, working from home
for Oracle Corporation, and hacks on GStreamer as he can.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="montgomery" id="montgomery"></a>
	<p><b>Xiph.org plans and projects, Monty Montgomery, Red Hat</b></p>
	<p>
Christopher (Monty) Montgomery is a founder of the Xiph.Org Foundation
and the creator of the open-source audio format Ogg Vorbis and other
popular open-source packages.  He holds a B.S. in Electrical
Engineering and Computer Science from the Massachusetts Institute of
Technology and a M.Eng. in Computer Engineering from Tokyo Institute
of Technology.  He is currently a Senior Engineer at the open source
software vendor Red Hat where he works on open desktop media software.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr><td>
	<p><b>Videowall, Marc Leeman, Barco</b></p>
	<a name="leeman" id="leeman"></a>
	<p>Marc Leeman has been an open source enthousiast since 1997. He has
a background in electrical engineering where he did research on
dynamic memory usage optimalisations in embedded systems. Since 2004,
he is working in Barco. After doing ports of GNU/Linux to embedded
systems for a couple years, he is currently developing streaming video
applications with GStreamer.</p>
<p>
He has three lovely daughters that use a GStreamer application to watch
their favourite television shows from the DVB-S Dreambox settop box.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="swain" id="swain"></a>
	<p><b>Interlacing and telecine, Robert Swain, Collabora</b></p>
	<p>
Robert Swain is a multimedia software developer with a strong and long-running interest in codecs and processing/transmission of digital audio and video. He learned to program on-the-fly while contributing to open source multimedia software projects including FFmpeg/libav and GStreamer.</p>
<p>
Since joining Collabora in 2009, he has worked on a broad range of topics such as GStreamer as a multimedia backend for Android, progressive download support for common video formats, PiTiVi pipeline optimisations, general camera improvements for Meego and dynamic, automated deinterlacing.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="bethencourt" id="bethencourt"></a>
	<p><b>Luis De Bethencourt, Collabora</b></p>
	<p></p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="droege" id="droege"></a>
	<p><b>Pulse Audio , Sebastian Droege, Collabora</b></p>
	<p>
Sebastian Dröge is working on GStreamer since early 2006 and nowadays is
one of the main developers. He also works on other open source projects
in his free time and is working for Collabora on GStreamer and related
technologies since 2008. Sebastian has a master's degree in computer
sciences.
</p>

	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="frisch" id="frisch"></a>
	<p><b>Blu-ray Authoring, Andreas Frisch, Dreambox</b></p>
	<p>Andreas, who likes to call himself Fraxinas in the online world, graduated 
from the University of Applied Sciences in Aschaffenburg with a degree in 
electrical engineering and information technology. Since writing his thesis 
paper about a streaming video server for set top boxes, he has been working 
for Dream Multimedia, the company which released the first Linux-based STB 
called &quot;Dreambox&quot;. Andreas is now responsible for the Gstreamer integration 
into Enigma2, the software for this embedded linux product line.
</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="schleef" id="schleef"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer in Broadcast and Web Streaming, David Schleef, Entropy Wave</b></p>
	<p>David Schleef is the founder and CEO of Entropy Wave, a San
Francisco based company providing products and services that
enable its customers to use open video technology such as WebM
and Ogg/Theora for archival, professional editing, broadcasting,
and content distribution.  David has been an active member in
the open source community for 15 years, working most recently on
projects such as GStreamer, a cross-platform multimedia framework,
the Dirac video codec, and various Xiph.org projects.
</p>

	</td></tr>

<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="burks" id="burks"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer for Engineering Video Processing Applications, Joshua Doe and Stephen Bruke, US Army</b></p>
	<p></p>

	</td></tr>

</table>

</body>
</page>
