<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
    %site-entities;
    ]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2010 Program </title>

<body lang="en-US" dir="LTR">

<h1>GStreamer Conference 2010</h1>
<h2>Cambridge, United Kingdom, 26th of October 2010</h2>

<table width="100%" border="1" bordercolor="#000000" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="0">
	
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Wim Taymans, Collabora Multimedia 
			</p>
			<p>
		Wim Taymans is one of the founders of the GStreamer project and the man behind the current GStreamer design. Wim got
		a long history in the development of multimedia software, starting with computer game development on the Commodore 64.
		Wim Taymans is a co-founder of Collabora Multimedia and is working on assisting Collabora Multimedia customers with the
		design and use of GStreamer.
			</p>
			<p>
		Wim Taymans will in his keynote be speaking about the current state of GStreamer and the development plans for GStreamer 1.0.
			</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">		
		<td>
		<p>Philippe Normand has worked at ENST-Bretagne (France) on home-care and domotic technologies for 
		elderly people. He too worked on the Elisa/Moovida media-center project at Fluendo.
		</p>
		<p>At Igalia he currently works on improving the HTML5 audio/video support in WebKitGTK+ with the GStreamer 
		multimedia framework. Philippe has a Master degree in Computer Sciences.</p>
		</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top">
		<td>
			<p>Mike Smith,Songbird 
			</p>
		<p>
		Mike Smith is the main GStreamer developer at Songbird, a company making the cross-platform music player Songbird.
		Mike will talk about their experiences with using GStreamer as a cross-platform media engine on Linux, Windows 
		and Mac OS X.
		</p></td></tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Edward Hervey, Collabora Multimedia 
			</p>
			<p>Edward Hervey founded PiTiVi during his final year at the EPITECH engineering school in Paris. 
			He soon found that PiTiVi's needs required improvements to the GStreamer framework, and began 
			developing them. At Collabora Multimedia, Edward manages the PiTiVi team and continues to contribute 
			substantially to the GStreamer project 
			</p>
		</td>


		<td>
			<p>A GStreamer based framework for adaptive streaming
			applications, Emanuele Quacchio,  ST Microelectronics</p>
		<p>Emanuele QUACCHIO *received the Master Degree in Electronic Engineering 
		from the Polytechnic University of Turin, Italy in 2003. He worked two 
		years as a researcher in the Dept. of Electronics of the same university 
		and joined STMicroelectronics at the AST-system R&amp;D group in 2006, where 
		he is currently working as a Senior System Engineer. His activities are 
		mainly focused on embedded SW development for STB/mobile platforms, 
		video compression standards and streaming protocols. He published and 
		co-authored several papers on the principal journals of engineering and 
		conferences. Since 2006 he has participated to a number of EU funded 
		projects (ASTRALS, SEA, P2PNext, COAST) and he has given lectures at 
		Polytechnic of Turin on video communication.</p>


		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Rob Clark has been working in the arm embedded world for more than 10 years, and
			playing with linux for even longer.  And most recently, gets to combine the
			two.  For the last year or so, he has been making GStreamer work with the
			hardware accelerated codecs and video on the TI OMAP4 platform.
			</p>
		</td>
		<td>
			<p>Implementing DLNA using GStreamer - Zeeshan Ali, Nokia</p>
			<p>Zeeshan Ali is a Lead Developer/Architect at Nokia OSSO in Helsinki, He started as a GStreamer 
			plugin and application developer and is known in the GNOME community for his video-whale project. 
			For the past three years, he had been obsessed with UPnP and in turn the GUPnP project and Rygel. 
			When he gets some time from his office work and GUPnP, he hangs around with his wife and tries to 
			learn some Finnish.
			</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Voip and Videoconferencing with Telepathy and Farstream -
			Olivier Crete, Collabora 
			</p>
			<p>
			Olivier Crête has degrees in software engineering, including one from École Polytechnique de Montréal. 
			He lives in Montréal, Canada, and is the lead developer and designer for the Farstream audio/video 
			conferencing framework. In his work for Collabora, he concentrates mainly on Farstream.
			</p>
		</td>
		<td>
			<p>Optimizing multimedia with Orc - David Schleef, Entropy Wave 
			</p>
			<p>David Schleef is one of the leading experts on open source multimedia. He has been active for 
			13+ years in leading and developing several open source projects, including GStreamer, Swfdec, Comedi, 
			Dirac/Schroedinger, and Liboil/Orc. His most recent project, Orc, allows developers to harness the 
			power of CPU vector extensions without having to write assembly code or intrinsics. Allegedly, he got 
			tired of writing yet another thousand lines of assembly code and wrote a program to write it for him.
			</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Case study - Tandberg and GStreamer, Håvard Graff, Tandberg 
			</p>
		</td></tr>
		<tr><td>
			<p>SLTV - live streaming for the masses – Luciana Fujii,
			Holoscopio</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Case study - Flumotion and GStreamer - Zaheer Merali</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Case study - GStreamer on
			Axis devices, Jonas Holmberg, Axis
			</p>
			<p>
			In 2006 Axis camera developers decided to implement a GStreamer based
			streaming application for their camera and video server hardware. Two
			years later the first GStreamer based Axis camera was released.
			</p><p>
			This case study will discuss lessons learned during development of a
			GStreamer based application on custom hardware.
			</p>
		</td></tr>
		<tr><td>
		<p>Andrey Nechypurenko and Maksym Parkachov</p>
		<p>Andrey Nechypurenko is currently working as a senior software engineer
		at General Electric. He has many years of experience in defining
		architecture and implementing large scale distributed real-time and
		embedded systems in automotive and industrial automation domain. As
		his hobby, Andrey is developing different kinds of ground and air
		vehicles which can be controlled over the Internet.</p>
		<p>
		Maksym Parkachov is working as senior CRM consultant at the Riverland
		GmbH. His expertise area lies in integration of the enterprise
		front-facing applications with industry standard back-ends,
		optimizations of parallel processing systems and data quality
		processes implementation . In his free time, he is building remote
		controlled embedded systems.</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>3D Stereoscopic and GStreamer, Martin Bisson</p>
		</td>
		<td>
			<p>Case Study - Intel SIMD elements in GStreamer, Josep Torra,
			Fluendo 
			</p>
			<p>
			Josep Torra holds a Computer Engineering degree from the Open
			University of Catalonia (UOC), Catalonia, Spain. He joined Fluendo as
			senior developer and became a part of the codec development team for
			embedded systems in 2006. He currently works as a Technical Lead for
			the team developing codecs and multimedia related projects in a wide
			range of platforms, from desktop to embedded systems.
			Embedded Linux development, HW accelerated decoders, and performance
			optimization techniques are of special interest for Josep. He is also
			a developer on the GStreamer project.</p>

		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>WebM and GStreamer, Sebastian Droge 
			</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr valign="top">
		
		<td>
			<p>Case study - Using gstreamer for building automated webcasting systems, Florent Thiery, Ubicast.eu 
			</p>
			<p>Florent Thiery is co-founder and C.T.O. of UbiCast, a small french company dedicated to providing 
			turnkey, automated multimedia capture appliances for the conference, training and educational market. 
			Based on the gstreamer framework and other open source technologies (notably, OpenCV, twisted and 
			Clutter), these solutions aim at lowering the complexity of producing and publishing video to the 
			Internet by automating as much tasks as possible for the end user. Being a gstreamer application 
			architect and developer, he focuses on audio/video capture devices, web streaming and computer vision 
			technologies.
 			</p>
		</td>
	</tr>

</table>

<p>
<b>Note:</b> there will be further GStreamer-related talks on October 27/28 as part of the
<a href="http://www.embeddedlinuxconference.com/elc_europe10/program.html">main CE Linux program</a>.
</p>

</body>
</page>
