<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
    %site-entities;
    ]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2010 Program </title>

<body lang="en-US" dir="LTR">

<h1>Speakers bio and abstracts - GStreamer Conference 2010</h1>
<h2>Cambridge, United Kingdom, 26th of October 2010</h2>
<p><a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference">Back to conference main page</a></p>
<p><a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/conference/gstreamer-conference-timetable.html">Back to conference timetable</a></p>
<table width="100%" border="1" bordercolor="#C0C0C0" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="2">
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="taymans" id="taymans"></a>
	<p><b>Keynote - GStreamer - Current and future development, Wim Taymans, Collabora Multimedia</b></p>
	<p>
	Wim Taymans is one of the founders of the GStreamer project and the man behind the current GStreamer design. Wim got
	a long history in the development of multimedia software, starting with computer game development on the Commodore 64.
	Wim Taymans is a co-founder of Collabora Multimedia and is working on assisting Collabora Multimedia customers with the
	design and use of GStreamer.
	</p>
	<p>
	Wim Taymans will in his keynote be speaking about the current state of the <a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org">GStreamer</a>
	project and the development plans for GStreamer 1.0.
	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="normand" id="normand"></a>
	<p><b>Webkit, HTML5 and GStreamer, Philippe Normand, Igalia</b></p>
	<p>Philippe Normand has worked at ENST-Bretagne (France) on home-care and domotic technologies for 
	elderly people. He too worked on the Elisa/Moovida media-center project at Fluendo. At Igalia 
	he currently works on improving the HTML5 audio/video support in WebKitGTK+ with 
	the GStreamer multimedia framework. Philippe has a Master degree in Computer Sciences.</p>
	<p>
	This talk will cover integrating a GStreamer-based media player in
	multiple <a href="http://webkit.org/">WebKit</a> ports to provide HTML5 audio/video support on a
	variety of platforms including (but not limited to) Linux, Mac OS X
	and Windows. It will describe the modifications done on the player first developed
	for the GTK+ WebKit port to be cross-platform and modular enough to be
	used by other ports such as WinCairo and the official Mac WebKit port.
	</p>
	<p>
	Other topics discussed will include the fullscreen video support
	implementation, a check-list explaining how to enable the GStreamer
	player for your WebKit port and a small HTML5 video showcase of the
	current WebKit ports supporting the GStreamer player.
	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="smith" id="smith"></a>
	<p><b>Cross platform development with GStreamer, Michael Smith, Songbird</b></p>
	<p>
	Michael Smith is the main GStreamer developer at Songbird, a company making the cross-platform music player Songbird.
	Michael will talk about their experiences with using GStreamer as a cross-platform media engine on Linux, Windows 
	and Mac OS X.
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will focus on the advantages and challenges when using GStreamer as a cross platform middleware based on 
	the experiences with developing the <a href="http://getsongbird.com/">Songbird</a> Music Player on Windows, MacOS X, Solaris and Linux, all using the GStreamer
	framework for media playback.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="hervey" id="hervey"></a>
	<p><b>Challenges of video editing in your pocket, Edward Hervey, Collabora Multimedia</b></p>
	<p>Edward Hervey started developing <a href="http://www.pitivi.org/">PiTiVi</a> during his final years at the EPITECH engineering school in Paris. He soon found that 
	PiTiVi's needs required improvements to the GStreamer framework, and began developing them. As one of the founders of Collabora 
	Multimedia, Edward manages the PiTiVi team and continues to contribute substantially to the GStreamer project.
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will focus on the <a href="http://blogs.gnome.org/edwardrv/2009/11/30/the-result-of-the-past-few-months-of-hacking/">
	GStreamer Editing Services (GES)</a> layer for GStreamer which adds support for high quality and low overhead 
	video editing in an easy manner with GStreamer. GES is developed with the embedded space in mind, but will also be useful for desktop 
	developers who want to add simple video editing support to their applications.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="quacchio" id="quacchio"></a>
	<p><b>A GStreamer based framework for adaptive streaming
	applications, Emanuele Quacchio,  ST Microelectronics</b></p>
	<p>Emanuele Quacchio received the Master Degree in Electronic Engineering 
	from the Polytechnic University of Turin, Italy in 2003. He worked two 
	years as a researcher in the Dept. of Electronics of the same university 
	and joined STMicroelectronics at the AST-system R&amp;D group in 2006, where 
	he is currently working as a Senior System Engineer. His activities are 
	mainly focused on embedded SW development for STB/mobile platforms, 
	video compression standards and streaming protocols. He published and 
	co-authored several papers on the principal journals of engineering and 
	conferences. Since 2006 he has participated to a number of EU funded 
	projects (ASTRALS, SEA, P2PNext, COAST) and he has given lectures at 
	Polytechnic of Turin on video communication.</p>
	<p>
	In this work we present novel gstreamer plugins that lay the groundwork for the development
	of adaptive streaming applications supporting the novel video coding standard known as
	Scalable Video Coding (SVC) , extension of state-of-art H.264/AVC standard.
	</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="clark" id="clark"></a>
	<p><b>GStreamer and OMAP4, Rob Clark, Texas Instruments</b></p>
	<p>Rob Clark has been working in the arm embedded world for more than 10 years, and
	playing with linux for even longer.  And most recently, gets to combine the
	two.  For the last year or so, he has been making GStreamer work with the
	hardware accelerated codecs and video on the TI OMAP4 platform.
	</p>
	<p>
	An overview of GStreamer based multimedia on TI OMAP4 linux platform.  For
	optimal integration of the accelerated video encoders and decoders, camera,
	and display we ran in to a number of missing features in GStreamer, such as
	support for rowstride, more flexible caps negotiation, zero copy crop/vstab,
	buffer padding and alignment requirements.  In addition, there is still
	optimization possible if cache operations (invalidate/clean) could be
	eliminated in pipelines where we know software is not touching the buffers,
	as would typically be the case on an SoC like OMAP4.  We would like to
	present how we've solved these problems currently, and how we could possibly
	solve them in GStreamer 1.0.</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="ali" id="ali"></a>
	<p><b>Implementing DLNA using GStreamer, Zeeshan Ali, Nokia</b></p>
	<p>Zeeshan Ali is a Lead Developer/Architect at Nokia MeeGo Computers division in Helsinki, He started as a GStreamer 
	plugin and application developer and is known in the GNOME community for his video-whale project. 
	For the past three years, he had been obsessed with UPnP and in turn the GUPnP project and <a href="http://live.gnome.org/Rygel">
	Rygel</a>. When he gets some time from his office work and GUPnP, he hangs around with his wife, plays Star Trek Online &amp; 
	Street Fighter in his spare time and sometimes tries to learn some Finnish.</p>
	<p>Rygel is a collection of DLNA (UPnP AV) services implementing the <a href="http://www.dlna.org">DLNA</a> standard for 
	interoperable multimedia devices, implemented through a plug-in mechanism. UPnP in simplest words is a set of protocols 
	that defines how different devices on a home network can seamlessly (without or with minimum configuration) communicate with 
	each other. This talk will introduce you to the current state of Rygel and give you an introduction how Rygel can be quickly 
	deployed to enable you to ship a DLNA-enabled device.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="crete" id="crete"></a>
	<p><b>Integrating VideoConferencing into Everyday Applications, Olivier Crete, Collabora</b></p>
	<p>
	Olivier Crete has been involved in free software since 2000. He's been the
	maintainer of GnomeICU (a Gnome ICQ client) since 2002 and a Gentoo
	developer since 2003, starting the amd64 port and also helping maintain
	various IM applications. He currently works for Collabora on GStreamer,
	the Farstream VoIP framework and its integration into Telepathy. 
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will discuss how until now, videoconferencing has lived in dedicated applications. 
	We've had instant messengers with VoIP, softphones, but they don't integrate
	into the everyday workflow. <a href="http://www.collabora.co.uk/projects/farstream/">Farstream</a>,
	 the next generation of Farsight, the GStreamer based VoIP and videoconferencing framework not only
	provides media handling to communication applications such as Empathy,
	Pidgin, aMSN and the Nokia Internet Tablets, but can also be used to
	integrate videoconferencing into everyday applications.</p>
	<p>This talk will give a brief introduction to Farstream and <a href="http://www.collabora.co.uk/projects/telepathy/">
	Telepathy</a> and how they integrate. I will then show how to integrate videoconferencing features
	into an application such as a non-linear editor. It will also demonstrate
	how easy it is for application developers to integrate such features
	into their applications and how useful it can be for users.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="schleef" id="schleef"></a>
	<p><b>Optimizing multimedia with Orc, David Schleef, Entropy Wave.</b></p>
	<p>David Schleef is one of the leading experts on open source multimedia. He has been active for 
	13+ years in leading and developing several open source projects, including GStreamer, Swfdec, Comedi, 
	Dirac/Schroedinger, and Liboil/Orc. His most recent project, Orc, allows developers to harness the 
	power of CPU vector extensions without having to write assembly code or intrinsics. Allegedly, he got 
	tired of writing yet another thousand lines of assembly code and wrote a program to write it for him.
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will present the <a href="http://code.entropywave.com/projects/orc/">Orc</a> library and set of tools for compiling and executing very simple programs that operate on arrays of data.  
	The “language” is a generic assembly language that represents many of the features available in SMD architectures, including 
	saturated addition and subtraction, and many arithmetic operations. The talk will also cover the recently released
	NEON backend for ORC.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="graff" id="graff"></a>
	<p><b>Case study - Tandberg and GStreamer, Håvard Graff, Tandberg</b></p>
	<p>
	Håvard was introduced to GStreamer when he started working for TANDBERG (now Cisco) three years ago, and has been in love ever since. 
	Håvard is particularly interested in dynamic pipeline-building, synchronization, MT-safeness and audio. When not trying to understand 
	caps-negotiation, Håvard tries to play the piano. Works on <a href="http://www.tandberg.com/personal-video-conferencing/pc-mac-video-movi-v2..jsp">
	Movi</a>, a cross-platform, telepresence application for the desktop. 
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will cover our experiences with gstreamer, how we work with it, management issues, 
	support, customizing and so on. We will also specifically look at the Movi application developed by Tandberg using GStreamer, 
	including an in depth look at how we &quot;do it&quot; Points of interest, challenges with dynamic live pipelines, plumbing solutions etc.
	We will also talk about acoustic echo cancelling in gstreamer including how we solved it, challenges, tips and hints.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="fujii" id="fujii"></a>
	<p><b>Landell - live streaming for the masses, Luciana Fujii, Holoscopio</b></p>
	<p>
	Luciana Fujii is the main developer of <a href="http://landell.holoscopio.com">Landell</a>
	, a free software designed to allow live recording and streaming with simple GTK+-based interface. In Holoscópio,
	she has also worked in embedded systems development. Luciana has a bachelor's degree in Computer Science.
	</p><p>
	Features of Landell include switching sources, picture-in-picture,
	watermark, multiple filters and multiple simultaneous outputs without
	stopping the pipeline.The presentation will show the challenges faced during Landell
	development, specially regarding dynamically changing a quite complex
	pipeline.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="merali" id="merali"></a>
	<p><b>Case study - Flumotion and GStreamer, Zaheer Merali</b></p>
	<p>
	Zaheer Merali is a long standing GStreamer developer, now working at Tandberg/Cisco as a senior software engineer. 
	He was at Flumotion for 4 1/2 years where he has heavily influenced the design and code of the open source Flumotion 
	streaming server.
	</p>
	<p>
	This talk will feature an introduction to <a href="http://www.flumotion.net/">Flumotion</a> the open source streaming server, the
	GStreamer, Python and Twisted powered streaming server. It will discuss how flumotion distributes 
	GStreamer pipelines across processes and how flumotion tries to ensure sync between different processes doing
	for example capture that could even be on different machines. We will also look at how flumotion streams to the 
	end user client, adminning a Flumotion streaming server and finally how to create your own Flumotion component.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="holmberg" id="holmberg"></a>
	<p><b>Case study - GStreamer on Axis devices, Jonas Holmberg, Axis</b></p>
	<p>
	Jonas Holmberg is a Master of Science in Computer Science from Sweden.
 	He works as an expert Software Engineer at Axis Communications, being an
	system architect and software developer.
	</p>
	<p>
	In 2006 Axis camera developers decided to implement a GStreamer based
	streaming application for their camera and video server hardware. Two
	years later the first GStreamer based Axis camera was released.
	</p><p>
	This case study will discuss lessons learned during development of a
	GStreamer based application on custom hardware.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr><td>
	<a name="nechypurenko" id="nechypurenko"></a>
	<p><b>Using ICE middleware with GStreamer to implement real-time
	QoS-aware video streaming for remotely controlled vehicle.
	, Andrey Nechypurenko and Maksym Parkachov</b></p>

	<p>Andrey Nechypurenko is currently working as a senior software engineer
	at General Electric. He has many years of experience in defining
	architecture and implementing large scale distributed real-time and
	embedded systems in automotive and industrial automation domain. As
	his hobby, Andrey is developing different kinds of ground and air
	vehicles which can be controlled over the Internet.</p>
	<p>
	Maksym Parkachov is working as senior CRM consultant at the Riverland
	GmbH. His expertise area lies in integration of the enterprise
	front-facing applications with industry standard back-ends,
	optimizations of parallel processing systems and data quality
	processes implementation . In his free time, he is building remote
	controlled embedded systems.</p>

	<p>
	Typically, remotely controlled vehicles are equipped with video camera
	to let the remote driver see surrounding environment. To enable
	precise control of the vehicle over the Internet, it is necessary to
	assure low video latency and ability to adapt to the changing network
	conditions. In addition, low power consumption is required to increase
	the battery-based operation time. In this paper we: a) outline our
	embedded control system based on BeagleBoard open hardware and
	Ångström Linux distribution; b) provide requirements, motivation and
	describe how we build real-time quality of service (QoS) aware video
	streaming solution with ICE open-source middleware and GStreamer on
	this platform; c) we contrast and compare our solution with
	RTP/RTCP-based streaming alternatives and d) provide performance
	measurements for our adaptation algorithms.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="bisson" id="bisson"></a>
	<p><b>3D Stereoscopic and GStreamer, Martin Bisson</b></p>
	<p>
	Martin Bisson has completed his Master's Degree in Computer Science at École Polytechnique de Montréal, working on a 3D visualization 
	tool for minimally invasive spine surgery.  During his studies, he worked for various high technology companies in the fields of 
	image and video processing as well as computer graphics, such as Matrox and Autodesk (Media &amp; Entertainment Division formerly 
	known as Discreet).  In 2008, he co-founded Float4 Interactive (www.float4.com), a creative technology company that develops interactive 
	systems for entertainment, advertising and design applications. 
	</p>
	<p>With recent developments in 3D video technology and its success, adding support now for this uprising technology will make 
	GStreamer an attractive choice for application developers.  The support has been implemented as part of a Google Summer of Code 
	project.  Different possible implementations, each with its own strengths and weaknesses, were considered, but a simple and 
	hopefully complete one was chosen.  ORC can be used for the CPU-intensive but easily parallelized task of generating anaglyph images.  
	Work still needs to be done, especially on support of different 3D display hardware..</p>
	</td></tr>
		
	<tr><td>
	<p><b>Case Study - Intel SIMD elements in GStreamer, Josep Torra, Fluendo</b></p>
	<a name="torra" id="torra"></a>
	<p>Josep Torra holds a Computer Engineering degree from the Open
	University of Catalonia (UOC), Catalonia, Spain. He joined Fluendo as
	senior developer and became a part of the codec development team for
	embedded systems in 2006. He currently works as a Technical Lead for
	the team developing codecs and multimedia related projects in a wide
	range of platforms, from desktop to embedded systems. Embedded Linux development, 
	HW accelerated decoders, and performance optimization techniques are of special interest for Josep. 
	He is also a developer on the GStreamer project.</p>
	<p>
	Intel C3100 (aka Canmore)and C4100 (aka Sodaville) are integrated system-on-a-chip solutions
	that could be used in set-top boxes to integrate the Internet on TVs. This talk discuss the
	work done at Fluendo to support the Moovida media center solution on Intels chipset and the 
	state of running these kind of applications on Linux systems.
	</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top" bgcolor="#C0C0C0"><td>
	<a name="droge" id="droge"></a>
	<p><b>WebM and GStreamer, Sebastian Dröge, Collabora Multimedia</b></p>
	<p>
	Sebastian Dröge is working on GStreamer since early 2006 and nowadays is
	one of the main developers. He is working for Collabora Multimedia since
	2008 and also works on other open source projects in his free time.
	Sebastian has a bachelor's degree in computer sciences and is currently
	finishing his master's degree.
	</p>
	<p>This year Google released the <a href="http://www.webmproject.org/">WebM</a> video format for the web. This talk presents the work done
	by Collabora Multimedia and Entropy Wave to support this format from day one in GStreamer and 
	how vendors can quickly and easily support WebM on their devices using GStreamer.</p>
	</td></tr>
	
	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="thiery" id="thiery"></a>
	<p><b>Case study - Using gstreamer for building automated webcasting systems, Florent Thiery, Ubicast.eu</b></p>
	<p>Florent Thiery is co-founder and C.T.O. of UbiCast, a small french company dedicated to providing 
	turnkey, automated multimedia capture appliances for the conference, training and educational market. 
	Based on the gstreamer framework and other open source technologies (notably, OpenCV, twisted and 
	Clutter), these solutions aim at lowering the complexity of producing and publishing video to the 
	Internet by automating as much tasks as possible for the end user. Being a gstreamer application 
	architect and developer, he focuses on audio/video capture devices, web streaming and computer vision 
	technologies.</p>
	</td></tr>

	<tr valign="top"><td>
	<a name="thiery" id="schmidt"></a>
	<p><b>Interactivity in GStreamer pipelines, Jan Schmidt, Oracle Corporation</b></p>
	<p>This talk will discuss the challenges encountered when implementing features such as DVD menu support 
	with GStreamer, and the solutions that were implemented. It will discuss how these can be used in other 
	scenarios, such as interactivity over the network, and Blu-ray disc support.</p>
	<p>Jan is a GStreamer maintainer. After leaving Fluendo in 2007, he moved to Ireland and joined Sun Microsystems 
	and subsequently Oracle on their acquisition of Sun in 2009. These days, he lives in Australia and hacks on 
	GStreamer as he can.</p>
	</td></tr>
</table>

<p>
<b>Note:</b> there will be further GStreamer-related talks on October 27/28 as part of the
<a href="http://www.embeddedlinuxconference.com/elc_europe10/program.html">main CE Linux program</a>.
</p>

</body>
</page>
