<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plug-ins</module-fancy>
  <name>Closer to the Edit</name>
  <version>0.10.19</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new release
in the 0.10.x stable series of the
GStreamer Good Plug-ins.
</p>
<p>
The 0.10.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.8.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.8.x series.
</p>

<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plug-ins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plug-ins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plug-in on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plug-ins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plug-in
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plug-ins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plug-ins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plug-ins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plug-ins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plug-ins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
<feature>shapewipe: moved from -bad to -good</feature>
<feature>avidemux: push mode seeking support</feature>
<feature>avidemux: drop video frames up to the desired keyframe after a seek</feature>
<feature>configure: cross-compilation fixes (use $PKG_CONFIG instead of pkg-config)</feature>
<feature>dvdepay: don't output frames until we have a header, fixes crash</feature>
<feature>flacdec: fix tag extraction in push mode</feature>
<feature>flvdemux: obtain the index from the end of an flv file in push mode</feature>
<feature>flvdemux: audio tags without any content are valid; indexing improvements</feature>
<feature>jpegdec: fix invalid memory access in parser</feature>
<feature>jitterbuffer: new buffering modes: low/high watermark buffering, rtp timestamps</feature>
<feature>matroskademux: seeking/segment fixes (esp. regression with gnonlin)</feature>
<feature>matroskademux: subtitle stream improvements (advance sparse streams in smaller steps)</feature>
<feature>multipartdemux: improve header mime-type parsing</feature>
<feature>qtdemux: fix ALAC codec-data handling; handle signed values in 3GPP location tag</feature>
<feature>qtdemux: fix frame rate cap regression; fix sample durations corner-case</feature>
<feature>qtdemux: Use the correct duration when comparing segments</feature>
<feature>pulsesink: avoid segfault when shutting down</feature>
<feature>pulsesink: return previous mute state if sink is not active at the moment</feature>
<feature>rtpbin: change how NTP time is calculated in RTCP, generating more accurate NTP timestamps if the system clock is synchronised with NTP or similar</feature>
<feature>rtpmp4gdepay: avoid division by 0 in corner case</feature>
<feature>v4l2sink: change rank to NONE so we don't try to autoplug it</feature>
<feature>videomixer: fix timestamping problems for input streams with different lengths</feature>
<feature>videomixer: fix problem when used with gnonlin (always send FLUSH_STOP)</feature>
  </features>

  <applications>
  </applications>

    <contributors>
	<person>Alessandro Decina</person>
	<person>Anders Skargren</person>
	<person>Brian Cameron</person>
	<person>David Hoyt</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Philippe Normand</person>
	<person>Robert Swain</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Stefan Kost</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Volker Grabsch</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

  <api>
    <additions>
<item>jitterbuffer::mode</item>
<item>rtpbin::buffer-mode</item>
    </additions>
  </api>

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>584536</id>
      <summary>[PLUGIN-MOVE] Move shapewipe to -good</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>587304</id>
      <summary>[jitterbuffer] don't handle correctly data burst from udpsrc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599292</id>
      <summary>Synchronizing two RTP streams from different devices using RTCP is inaccurate.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>604711</id>
      <summary>Handling of mime type in multipartdemux</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>608026</id>
      <summary>[videomixer] timestamping problems</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>608843</id>
      <summary>[flacdec] Can't read tags in push mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610004</id>
      <summary>GST_CXXFLAGS should contain GST_CFLAGS</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610053</id>
      <summary>matroska fails to build with Sun Studio</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610238</id>
      <summary>Avoid an assertion in the rtspsrc element which abort the client application</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610265</id>
      <summary>gstrtpmp4gdepay issuing a SIGFPE crashing an application</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610280</id>
      <summary>[qtdemux] issue with corrupted 3gp file</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610296</id>
      <summary>[qtdemux] Confusion with gst/qt segments</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610337</id>
      <summary>pulsesink: gst_pulsesink_get_mute: set result earlier.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610483</id>
      <summary>[jpegdec] invalid memory access</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610556</id>
      <summary>Memory violation when starting to decode a running DV PAL RTP stream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610839</id>
      <summary>Unable to cross compile gst-plugins-good</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610894</id>
      <summary>send FLUSH_STOP after FLUSH_START in videomixer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>611501</id>
      <summary>[regression] matroskademux fails to output anything on some seeks</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>609724</id>
      <summary>Add translator comment for %s in pulsesink</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
