<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.1.4</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>

<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Akihiro Tsukada</person>
	<person>Andoni Morales Alastruey</person>
	<person>Chris Bass</person>
	<person>David Schleef</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Kishore Arepalli</person>
	<person>Lubosz Sarnecki</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Michael Olbrich</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sjoerd Simons</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>Youness Alaoui</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>705371</id>
      <summary>souphttpsrc: Does network operations from the state change thread</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>590768</id>
      <summary>GstPulseSrc should allow swapping the device used by the stream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637754</id>
      <summary>multipartdemux: time stamp output buffer based on first input buffer not last</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>694445</id>
      <summary>pulsesink: add support for AAC pass-through</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>700264</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: ignores first editlist</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>702988</id>
      <summary>gdkpixbufoverlay: crashes if any property changes during  playback when location property is not set</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705108</id>
      <summary>rtpgstpay: Add a config-interval property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705442</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: prints warnings on seek</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705449</id>
      <summary>avidemux: sends stream_start event without group_id</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705553</id>
      <summary>rtph264pay: Entries of SPS and PPS duplicated</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705760</id>
      <summary>rtspsrc produces GLib error</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705959</id>
      <summary>souphttpsrc deprecated symbols</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>706076</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: failed assertion for fragmented mp4 (DASH) streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>706642</id>
      <summary>avimux: unmap the correct buffer</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
