<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.1.90</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>

<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Alex Ashley</person>
	<person>Andreea Fulger</person>
	<person>Bernhard Miller</person>
	<person>Christoph Reiter</person>
	<person>David Holroyd</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Rico Tzschichholz</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seán de Búrca</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>646963</id>
      <summary>rtpmanager: Only update last_rtcp_send_time when actually sending a report</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>687657</id>
      <summary>rtpsession: Demux RTCP buffers from the RTP stream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>695090</id>
      <summary>rganalysis: fix tests</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>702004</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: add support for the avc3 sample entry format of the AVC file  format</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>704950</id>
      <summary>videomixer: add colorspace conversion</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>705371</id>
      <summary>souphttpsrc: Does network operations from the state change thread</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>706955</id>
      <summary>autoaudiosink/autovideosink: Introduce &quot; sync &quot; property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707042</id>
      <summary>udpsrc binds to INADDR_ANY instead of multicast group address</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707303</id>
      <summary>flacenc: 'Got data flow before stream-start event' warnings</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707340</id>
      <summary>qtmux: should NOT use PTS if DTS is missing</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707411</id>
      <summary>qtmux: what is purpose of MAX_TOLERATED_LATENESS?</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707530</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Handle segments correctly in push mode seeks</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707688</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: leaking buffer and caps when parsing attachments</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707734</id>
      <summary>rtp: add payloader and depayloader for 24bit raw audio</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707758</id>
      <summary>v4l2: Incorrect UV plane stride value for NV12/NV21 formats</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707886</id>
      <summary>videomixer: build fails due to unrenamed files if orc is not installed</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707933</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: Wrong UTF8 detection causes wrong detection of subtitle encoding</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>708131</id>
      <summary>videomixer: undefined reference to `videomixer_video_convert_orc_convert_I420_BGRA'</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
