<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.11.91</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release candidate of the
stable 1.12 release series. The 1.12 release series is adding new features on
top of the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8 and 1.10 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Full release notes will be provided with the 1.12.0 release, highlighting all
the new features, bugfixes, performance optimizations and other important
changes.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
    <contributors>
	<person>ChangBok Chae</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>George Kiagiadakis</person>
	<person>Jürgen Sachs</person>
	<person>Lyon Wang</person>
	<person>Nirbheek Chauhan</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Todor Tomov</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
	<person>Xavier Claessens</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>767498</id>
      <summary>splitmuxsink: Not handling FLUSH events correctly</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778337</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: sample_description_index not evaluated when parsing the stsd-box</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778830</id>
      <summary>v4l2dec: Fix race when going from PAUSED to READY</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>779106</id>
      <summary>flvdemux: remove duplicated segment initialization</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>780904</id>
      <summary>rtprtxqueue: implement handling of the max-size-time property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781008</id>
      <summary>scaletempo: Fix GAP events handle issue when set rate</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781025</id>
      <summary>tests: fix leak in splitmux test</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781119</id>
      <summary>v4l2: No timestamp set when importing dma buffer on V4L2_OUTPUT interface</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781266</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Properly reset demuxer when all streams are EOS</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781270</id>
      <summary>qtdemux, dash: segmentation fault on representation change</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781304</id>
      <summary>rtspsrc: Use GST_ELEMENT_ERROR_WITH_DETAILS</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781319</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Reset adapter in more discontinuity cases</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>781362</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Fix leak on QtDemuxStreamStsdEntry</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
