<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.11.2</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.11 release series. The 1.11 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8 and 1.10 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.11 release series
will lead to the stable 1.12 release series in the next weeks. Any newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Full release notes will be provided at some point during the 1.11 release
cycle, highlighting all the new features, bugfixes, performance optimizations
and other important changes.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arnaud Vrac</person>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Brendan Shanks</person>
	<person>David Warman</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Enrico Jorns</person>
	<person>Georg Lippitsch</person>
	<person>Guillaume Desmottes</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Jean-Christophe Trotin</person>
	<person>Jochen Henneberg</person>
	<person>Jonas Holmberg</person>
	<person>Juan Pablo Ugarte</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Matt Staples</person>
	<person>Miguel París Díaz</person>
	<person>Nick Kallen</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Rahul Bedarkar</person>
	<person>Reynaldo H. Verdejo Pinochet</person>
	<person>Santiago Carot-Nemesio</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Søren Juul</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vivia Nikolaidou</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>778690</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Possible bug on gst-1.11 gst_element_seek</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>736752</id>
      <summary>mp4mux/qtmux: Add HEVC support</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761761</id>
      <summary>splitmuxsink: Caps changes not handled</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>766177</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Critical errors reported playing mp4 file with only xmp tags</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>768762</id>
      <summary>tests: qtmux and matroskamux reported as leaking by the leaks tracer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>774209</id>
      <summary>splitmuxsink: Add option for timecode-based split</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>775440</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Use upstream's StreamFlags if there are</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>775817</id>
      <summary>rtph265pay: fix config-interval handling</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>776714</id>
      <summary>rtpmanager: enhance RTP statistics by recording nacks sent/received per source too</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>776715</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Skip seeking query if upstream format is time</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>776899</id>
      <summary>v4l2: Remove usage and definition of LOG_CAPS macro</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777100</id>
      <summary>qtmux: Write tapt atom for MOV files if PAR not 1/1</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777182</id>
      <summary>rtxqueue: Expose basic statistics as properties.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777330</id>
      <summary>v4l2bufferpool: remove duplicated line of code</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777331</id>
      <summary>qtmux: Don't write Sync Sample Atom for ProRes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777540</id>
      <summary>isomp4: Unable to create streams playable with MSE</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778013</id>
      <summary>rtpsession: relate received FIRs and PLIs to source</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778330</id>
      <summary>qtmux: Creates two edit lists with reserved-* options enabled</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778389</id>
      <summary>imagefreeze can return erroneous results for an accept caps query</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>776962</id>
      <summary>flacenc: Conversion from m4a encapsuled alac to flac fail with: Could not initialize supporting library.</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
