<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.7.2</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.7 release series. The 1.7 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4 and 1.6 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.7 release series
will lead to the stable 1.8 release series in the next weeks. Any newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately
during the unstable 1.7 release series.
</p>
<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Aleix Conchillo Flaqué</person>
	<person>Alex Ashley</person>
	<person>Antonio Ospite</person>
	<person>George Kiagiadakis</person>
	<person>Hyunjun Ko</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Luis de Bethencourt</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Miguel París Díaz</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Nirbheek Chauhan</person>
	<person>Ognyan Tonchev</person>
	<person>Pablo Anton</person>
	<person>Philippe Normand</person>
	<person>Piotr Drąg</person>
	<person>Reynaldo H. Verdejo Pinochet</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Steven Hoving</person>
	<person>Stian Selnes</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Thijs Vermeir</person>
	<person>Tim Sheridan</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vineeth TM</person>
	<person>Vivia Nikolaidou</person>
	<person>Víctor Manuel Jáquez Leal</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>617563</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: pelicula.mkv doesn't preroll/play due to audio track without data</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>709839</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: file with late audio stream start does not preroll</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>720388</id>
      <summary>deinterlace: handle unsupported features caps in passthrough mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>735673</id>
      <summary>interleave: the example in the documentation does not work</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>741280</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: Send GAP events for non sparse streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754773</id>
      <summary>rtp: Implement VP9 payloader and depayloader</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755736</id>
      <summary>v4l2transform: configure output pool to use min_buffer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>757290</id>
      <summary>gdkpixbufoverlay crash</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>759293</id>
      <summary>rtpbin: add &quot; get-session &quot; property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>759780</id>
      <summary>v4l2: deviceprovider: Add the device and sysfs paths to the GstDevice properties</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760774</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: fix framerate calculation for fragmented format</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760779</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: fix framerate calculation for fragmented format in push mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760781</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: handling zero segment-duration edit list</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760905</id>
      <summary>taginject: Unable to add tags with spaces using example pipeline from docs</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760995</id>
      <summary>deinterlace: Do passthrough if downstream only supports interlaced</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761094</id>
      <summary>unintialized variable warnings (gcc 5.1)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761144</id>
      <summary>matroskamux: use A_AAC instead of A_AAC/MPEGx/y</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761670</id>
      <summary>jpegdec: Possible endless loop if file is corrupt</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761705</id>
      <summary>POTFILES.in is out of date</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761769</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: incorrectly sets caps of CENC encrypted streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762057</id>
      <summary>tests: rtpmux: Fix element memory leak</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762117</id>
      <summary>avidemux: Fix string memory leak</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762185</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: Simple implementation of GST_SEEK_FLAG_TRICKMODE_KEY_UNITS</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762211</id>
      <summary>rtpjitterbuffer: Don't drop packets after big gap</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
