<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.8.3</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce the third bugfix release in the stable
1.8 release series of your favourite cross-platform multimedia framework!
</p>
<p>
This release only contains bugfixes and it is safe to update from 1.8.x. For a
full list of bugfixes see <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=VERIFIED&amp;classification=Platform&amp;limit=0&amp;list_id=145400&amp;order=bug_id&amp;product=GStreamer&amp;query_format=advanced&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;target_milestone=1.8.3">Bugzilla</a>.
</p>
<p>
See <a href="&site;/releases/1.8/">&site;/releases/1.8/</a> for the full release notes.
</p>
<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

      <contributors>
	<person>Brad Lackey</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Jonas Holmberg</person>
	<person>Jürgen Slowack</person>
	<person>Miguel París Díaz</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Reynaldo H. Verdejo Pinochet</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Thomas Bluemel</person>
	<person>Thomas Scheuermann</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>767666</id>
      <summary>splitmuxsink: infinite change_state loop</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>747275</id>
      <summary>jackaudiosink: hangs when jackd exits</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>766025</id>
      <summary>rtpsession: race condition accessing ssrcs hash table</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>766970</id>
      <summary>aacparse: sticky event criticals with RTL HD mpeg-ts stream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>767496</id>
      <summary>flvdemux: won't parse a date string with trailing whitespace</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>767680</id>
      <summary>rtph265pay: fix nal type parsing an sps/pps/vps insertion via config-interval property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>767980</id>
      <summary>udpsrc: Receiving multicast packets from all addresses, not just the configured</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>768232</id>
      <summary>rtspsrc: protocols aren't reset after rtsp redirect</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>768268</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Push caps only when it was updated</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>768509</id>
      <summary>matroskamux: Segmentation fault in string comparison</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>768623</id>
      <summary>udpsrc: There is no struct in_pktinfo on FreeBSD</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769514</id>
      <summary>splitmuxsink: Deadlock</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769773</id>
      <summary>multiudpsink: Randomly ceases to send to clients</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
