<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-good</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Good Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.9.90</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of the
stable 1.10 release series. The 1.10 release series is adding new features on
top of the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6 and 1.8 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
<i>"Such ingratitude.  After all the times I've saved your life."</i>
</p>
<p>
A collection of plugins you'd want to have right next to you on the
battlefield.  Shooting sharp and making no mistakes, these plugins have it
all: good looks, good code, and good licensing.  Documented and dressed up
in tests.  If you're looking for a role model to base your own plugin on,
here it is.
</p>
<p>
If you find a plot hole or a badly lip-synced line of code in them,
let us know - it is a matter of honour for us to ensure Blondie doesn't look
like he's been walking 100 miles through the desert without water.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that we consider to have good quality
  code, correct functionality, our preferred license (LGPL for the plugin
  code, LGPL or LGPL-compatible for the supporting library).
We believe distributors can safely ship these plugins.
People writing elements should base their code on these elements.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Georg Lippitsch</person>
	<person>Havard Graff</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Stian Selnes</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Thomas Bluemel</person>
	<person>Thomas Klausner</person>
	<person>Thomas Scheuermann</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
	<person>Wonchul Lee</person>
	<person>Xabier Rodriguez Calvar</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>751559</id>
      <summary>qtmux: Implement the preset interface.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>766990</id>
      <summary>multifilesink: 'buffer'-mode writes no longer atomic (regression)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769278</id>
      <summary>aacparse: a few fixes and improvements for LOAS parsing</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769757</id>
      <summary>rtpjitterbuffer: Fix calculating next_seqnum when dropping old buffers from a full queue.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769768</id>
      <summary>rtpjitterbuffer: lots of improvements around RTX</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770951</id>
      <summary>qtdemux: Crash with no cenc auxiliary offset available</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771272</id>
      <summary>jackaudiosink: hangs when jackd changes sample rate and/or buffer size</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771278</id>
      <summary>udpsrc: Compilation error on NetBSD</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771395</id>
      <summary>autodetect: Use gst_bin_set_suppressed_flags() API</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>772143</id>
      <summary>qtmux: Don't calculate PTS offset and DTS with GST_CLOCK_TIME_NONE</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>772228</id>
      <summary>tagschecking: Unit test fails because it sends untimestamped buffers to qtdemux</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
