<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Download</title>
  <body>

<h2>Download GStreamer</h2>

<p>
In general, you should find packages that were specifically made for your
distribution.  Do not compile from source yourself unless you are certain
you have to or want to.  Do not compile from Git unless you really need
some specific feature that is not released yet, or want to help out developing
GStreamer.
</p>

<DL>
  <DT>Linux</DT>
  <DD>Most, if not all, Linux distributions provide packages of GStreamer.
  You should find these in your distribution's package repository.
  <BR/>
  Note that some distributions split the GStreamer plugins up further than the
  upstream sources. Additionally, some distributions do not include the
  gst-plugins-bad, gst-plugins-ugly, and gst-ffmpeg packages in their main
  repository, for legal reasons.
  </DD>

  <DT>OpenBSD</DT>
  <DD>Packages for various architectures are available, see the <A href="http://openports.se/multimedia/gstreamer-0.10">OpenBSD ports</A> page.</DD>

  <DT>Windows</DT>
  <DD>The GStreamer project itself to not provide Windows binaries at this point unfortunately. However there are a couple of good options provided by the wider community.
    <p>
    The <a href="http://www.gstreamer-winbuild.ylatuya.es/doku.php?id=start">GStreamer winbuilds project</a> for instance has provided up-to-date binaries of GStreamer and plugin packages for some time now.
    </p>
    <p>
    Developers wishing to build GStreamer on Windows using MSVC may want to look at
    <A href="http://projects.collabora.co.uk/~oleavr/OABuild/">OABuild</A> which provides a
    fast and convenient way to build GStreamer, GTK+, D-Bus, Telepathy (and
    .NET bindings for all of them) on Windows, without requiring mingw/cygwin.
    </p>
  </DD>

  <DT>Symbian</DT>
  <DD>The sources of the initial port of GStreamer are available for <a href="&site;/src/symbian/gstreamer_source.zip">download</a>.
    <BR/>
    Releated binary packages are also <a href="&site;/pkg/symbian/gstreamer_binaries.zip">available</a>.
  </DD>

  <DT>Source</DT>
  <DD>Check our <A href="&site;/modules/">modules</A> page, or
    go straight to our <A href="&site;/src/">source download directory</A>.</DD>
</DL>
  </body>
</page>
