<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer Conference 2011</title>

  <body>
<table>
<tr><td>
<h1>GStreamer Conference 2011</h1>
<h2>October 24 - 25, 2011 · Clarion Congress Hotel · Prague, Czech Republic</h2>
<p>
<p><b>This years conference is over, but all the talks can be viewed online at <a href="http://gstconf.ubicast.tv/channels/#conferences2011">
gstconf.ubicast.tv</a> thanks to our recording partner <a href="http://www.ubicast.tv">Ubicast</a>.</b>
</p>
After a successful launch last year in Cambridge, UK, we are very happy to invite everyone to the
second annual GStreamer Conference. This year we will be co-hosting with the <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linux-kernel-summit">
Linux Kernel Summit</a> and hold the event at the Clarion Congress Hotel in Prague, Czech Republic.
</p>
<p>
This year we decided to broaden the scope a bit for the GStreamer Conference, by including talks from a wide range of related projects and technologies. This means that this year in addition to a lot of great talks about GStreamer you can also learn about latest developments with the WebM format, whats new in Pulse Audio and a lot more.
</p>
<p>
The lead keynote event this year will be GStreamer maintainer Wim Taymans talking about GStreamer 1.0, which will be out before the end of the year. This event will be your best chance to hear about whats new in GStreamer 1.0 and what advantages it will offer your application and product.
</p>
<h2>Technologies covered</h2>
<p>
We have a long list of topics to be presented like:
</p>

<ul>
<li>GStreamer 1.0</li>
<li>WebM and VP8</li>
<li>Pulse Audio development report</li>
<li>Designing complex pipelines with GStreamer</li>
<li>Blu-ray playback and GStreamer</li>
<li>Updates on latest Xiph.org and Vorbis developments</li>
<li>GStreamer, Webkit and HTML5</li>
<li>Case studies on GStreamer deployments</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td valign="top">
<h1>Platinum Sponsor</h1>
<p>
<a href="http://www.collabora.com/projects/gstreamer/"><img src="sponsor_150x49_collabora.png" alt="Collabora" height="49" width="150" /></a>
</p>
<h2>Silver Sponsors</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://www.fluendo.com"><img src="sponsor_149x36_fluendo.png" alt="Fluendo" height="36" width="149" /></a>
</p>
<p>
<a href="http://www.google.com"><img src="sponsor_150x50_google.png" alt="Google" height="50" width="150" /></a>
</p>
<h2>Special Media Partners</h2>
<p>
<a href="http://www.ubicast.eu/"><img src="sponsor_150x45_UbiCast.png" alt="Ubi Cast" height="45" width="150" /></a>
</p>
<p>
<small>
Interested in <a href="&site;/conference/2011/gstreamer-sponsor.pdf">becoming a sponsor?</a></small>
</p>
</td></tr>
</table>
<h2>Registration</h2>
<p>
Registration for GStreamer Conference 2011 is closed.
</p>
<h2>Full Program</h2>
<p>
We have the <a href="gstreamer-conference-timetable.html">full schedule for the conference</a> now online, including <a href="speakers.html"> abstracts and speaker biographies</a>. 
</p>

<h2>Who Should Join?</h2>
<p>
Anyone interested in open source multimedia is encouraged to join us at the GStreamer Conference 2011.
If you are a hobbyist or a student interested in the field of multimedia, or working for a company
using or looking to use GStreamer in their products, then this is the perfect event for you to network
at and learn more about the latest technological breakthroughs in and around GStreamer. The talks 
will target both developers and managers alike.
</p>
<p>Following on from the GStreamer Conference 2011 and the Linux Kernel Summit, at the same venue, is the <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/embedded-linux-conference-europe/">
Embedded Linux Conference Europe</a> and <a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon-europe">LinuxCon Europe</a>, so combining these events with
the GStreamer Conference might be a good idea for many of our attendees.
</p>
<h2>Hotel and Travel</h2>
<p>
The simplest option if you are attending it to book yourself a room at the <a href="http://www.cchp.cz/en/bookingconf/?price_group=32768&amp;hotel_id=2679&amp;service_model=2">
Clarion Congress Hotel Prague</a> as you would then be staying at the venue. If you use our link you will get our special conference rates at the hotel. There is
of course no requirement to stay at the hotel and you can of course use any lodging of your choosing and still attend the conference.
</p>
<p>
The closest airport is the Ruzyne International Airport and for those arriving by others means the conference center got a <a href="http://cchp.cz/en/about-us/#/2174&amp;2175">
page with directions for how to reach the Clarion Congress hotel</a>.</p>
<p>
We got the following two documents put together by some local volunteers about some <a href="&site;/conference/2011/Prague-Food.pdf">good restaurants</a> and <a href="&site;/conference/2011/Prague-Nightlife.pdf">night life</a> options while in Prague.

</p>
<p>
<table>
<tr><td><img src="http://www.cchp.cz/image-cache/crop-524x300/448-exterier_298x168.png" width="298" height="168"/>
</td></tr>
<tr><td><b>Clarion Congress Hotel, Prague</b></td></tr>
</table>
</p>
<p>If you have any questions about the GStreamer Conference please contact <a href="mailto:christian.schaller@collabora.co.uk">Christian Schaller</a>.</p>
<p><i>If you want information on last years conference you will find that on the <a href="&site;/conference/2010">GStreamer Conference 2010</a> website.</i></p>
  </body>
</page>
