<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-bad</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Bad Plug-ins</module-fancy>
  <name>Pink Noise</name>
  <version>0.10.21</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new release
in the 0.10.x stable series of the
GStreamer Bad Plug-ins.
</p>
<p>
The 0.10.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.8.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.8.x series.
</p>

<p>
<i>"That an accusation?"</i>
</p>
<p>
No perfectly groomed moustache or any amount of fine clothing is going to
cover up the truth - these plug-ins are Bad with a capital B.
They look fine on the outside, and might even appear to get the job done, but
at the end of the day they're a black sheep. Without a golden-haired angel
to watch over them, they'll probably land in an unmarked grave at the final
showdown.
</p>
<p>
Don't bug us about their quality - exercise your Free Software rights,
patch up the offender and send us the patch on the fastest steed you can
steal from the Confederates. Because you see, in this world, there's two
kinds of people, my friend: those with loaded guns and those who dig.
You dig.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plug-ins that aren't up to par compared to the
rest.  They might be close to being good quality, but they're missing something
- be it a good code review, some documentation, a set of tests, a real live
maintainer, or some actual wide use.  If the blanks are filled in they might be
upgraded to become part of either gst-plugins-good or gst-plugins-ugly,
depending on the other factors.
If the plug-ins break, you can't complain - instead, you can fix the
problem and send us a patch, or bribe someone into fixing them for you.
New contributors can start here for things to work on.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plug-ins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plug-ins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plug-ins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plug-ins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
    <feature>alsaspdif: removed alsaspdifsink element (replaced by alsasink device=spdif)</feature>
    <feature>metadata: remove metadata plugin</feature>
    <feature>jack: jack plugin has moved to gst-plugins-good (0.10.27)</feature>
    <feature>selector: input-selector and output-selector have moved to GStreamer core (0.10.32)</feature>
    <feature>valve: has moved to gstreamer core (0.10.32)</feature>
    <feature>applemedia: new plugin for Apple multimedia APIs (avfvideosrc, celvideosrc, qtkitvideosrc, miovideosrc, vth264decbin, vth264encbin, vtdec, vtenc)</feature>
    <feature>applemedia: new iOS video source based on AVFoundation</feature>
    <feature>y4mdec: new y4mdec element</feature>
    <feature>dcaparse: new dts/dca audio parser</feature>
    <feature>camerabin2: new camerabin element (work-in-progress, experimental)</feature>
    <feature>opencv: new plugin with elements facedetect, faceblur, edgedetect, cvsobel, cvsmooth, cvlaplace, cverode, cvequalizehist, cvdilate, textwrite, templatematch, pyramidsegment</feature>
    <feature>interlace: new element</feature>
    <feature>geometrictransform: new rotate element</feature>
    <feature>jp2kdecimator: add a JPEG2000 decimator element (drop details without reencoding)</feature>
    <feature>audioparsers: add dcaparse, a dts/dca parser, and mpegaudioparse (mp3parse replacement)</feature>
    <feature>autoconvert: add autovideoconvert, an autoconvert based video format converter</feature>
    <feature>checksumsink, chopmydata: new debug elements</feature>
    <feature>dvbsuboverlay: new element to overlay DVB subtitle</feature>
    <feature>rsvgoverlay: new element for scalable and relative svg overlay with cairo</feature>
    <feature>qtmux: add new ismlmux element, for fragmented isml major brand</feature>

    <feature>ac3parse: properly parse E-AC3 frame header and use proper EAC-3 caps</feature>
    <feature>ac3parse: relax BSID checking, performance improvements</feature>
    <feature>applemedia mtapi: update to reflect new API on iOS 4.x</feature>
    <feature>applemedia vtenc: bump H.264 level from 1.3 to 3.0</feature>
    <feature>applemedia vtenc: remove keyframe enforcement workaround</feature>
    <feature>applemedia celapi: update to reflect new API on iOS 4.x</feature>
    <feature>applemedia cvapi: add wrapper for IO surface access</feature>
    <feature>audioparse: add support for setting the channel-positions</feature>
    <feature>audioparsers: increase ranks to enable auto-plugging (incl. new mp3 parser)</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: enhancements for timestamp marked framed formats</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: increase keyframe awareness</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: perform bitrate handling and posting after newsegment sending</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: post duration message if average bitrates is updated</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: prevent indefinite resyncing</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: add index support, seek table and accurate seek support</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: support reverse playback</feature>
    <feature>baseparse: use determined seekability in answering SEEKING query</feature>
    <feature>basevideo: Add handling of GstForceKeyUnit events</feature>
    <feature>basevideodecoder: add capture pattern handling; don't blow away field information</feature>
    <feature>bayer2rgb: add format=bggr/etc. to caps, add framerate to the sink caps</feature>
    <feature>camerabin: add "preview-source-filter","ready-for-capture", "idle" properties</feature>
    <feature>camerabin: change "zoom" property from int to float</feature>
    <feature>camerabin: enable all conversion flags by default to make it work out-of-the-box everywhere</feature>
    <feature>coloreffects: Add chromahold effect</feature>
    <feature>cog: improvements in colorspace and scaler; add fast paths for colorspace conversion</feature>
    <feature>colorspace: revive element and add support for many more pixellayouts/colorspaces</feature>
    <feature>colorspace: add support for SDTV/HDTV YUV conversions</feature>
    <feature>dtmfsrc: Make the dtmfsrc accept events sent with gst_element_send_event</feature>
    <feature>tools: misc. improvements to element-maker tool</feature>
    <feature>faac: handle trailing encoder output</feature>
    <feature>faad: support reverse playback; cater for decoder delay and renegotiation</feature>
    <feature>faad: tweak output buffer timestamping</feature>
    <feature>flacparse: don't drop the last frame if it is followed by garbage</feature>
    <feature>flacparse: don't parse the complete FLAC frames but only look for valid frame headers (for performance)</feature>
    <feature>flacparse: fix picture parsing, fix parsing with unknown framesizes</feature>
    <feature>flacparse: parse seektable</feature>
    <feature>frei0r: add support for the FREI0R_PATH environment variable</feature>
    <feature>frei0r: fix crashes if plugins don't provide correct property information</feature>
    <feature>frei0r: fix scanning of plugin subdirectories and support different vendors</feature>
    <feature>frei0r: update frei0r interface specification to 1.2</feature>
    <feature>gaudieffects: avoid divide by 0 in burn element, make filter parameters dynamic and controllable</feature>
    <feature>id3mux: map GST_TAG_ALBUM_ARTIST, give PRIMARY rank</feature>
    <feature>invtelecine: Fix name of 30p/60i pattern</feature>
    <feature>jasperdec: don't fail hard on decoding error</feature>
    <feature>jifmux: detect EOI correctly; do not limit the size of the image on 16bits</feature>
    <feature>jp2kenc: Emit SOP markers in every codestream packet</feature>
    <feature>jpegparse: avoid infinite loop when resyncing; discard incomplete image</feature>
    <feature>kate: add segment tracking, and various other improvements</feature>
    <feature>kate: ensure the kate pad does not shoot ahead of the video pad</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsdemux: extract language for DVB subtitle streams</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsdemux: enable gather_pes only for DVB subtitle private streams</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsdemux: fix re-syncing on invalid data after seek</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsmux: Initialize PES packet before getting the header size</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsmux: Set adaptation flag when appropriate</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsmux: Set random_access_indicator for keyframes</feature>
    <feature>mpegtsparse: send TDT tables messages in a serialized event downstream</feature>
    <feature>ofa: Call g_object_notify() after the fingerprint was created</feature>
    <feature>pcapparse: Add support for Linux Cooked Capture (SLL) frames</feature>
    <feature>photography: add missing property and cabability flag for noise reduction</feature>
    <feature>photography: Add "zoom" and "image-preview-supported-caps" interface properties</feature>
    <feature>photography: add gst_photography_{set,get}_noise_reduction() and CAPS_NOISE_REDUCTION flag</feature>
    <feature>qtmux: add support for fragmented mp4</feature>
    <feature>qtmux: add "streamable" property to avoid building fragmented mfra index</feature>
    <feature>qtmux: timestamp tracking fixes and many other fixes</feature>
    <feature>resindvd: attempt to use glib language setting for DVD menus/audio</feature>
    <feature>resindvd: improve error messages on read errors; button state tracking fixes</feature>
    <feature>rfbsrc: fail more gracefully if source gets disconnected or geometry changes</feature>
    <feature>sdlvideosink: re-enable YVYU and UYVY support</feature>
    <feature>sdpdemux: error out if no streams found in sdp message</feature>
    <feature>sdpdemux: redirect SDP with an rtsp control URL and add property to disable redirect</feature>
    <feature>ssim: add I420 support</feature>
    <feature>tiger: outline text by default, to make it easier to read</feature>
    <feature>winks: add property probing support; fix framerate fraction range mapping</feature>
    <feature>winks: ignore unsupported formats; work around shutdown deadlock</feature>
    <feature>winks: performance improvements</feature>
    <feature>zbar: make scanner cache optional, disable it by default</feature>
    <feature>zbar: use correct strides, support more formats</feature>
  </features>

  <applications>
  </applications>
    <contributors>
	<person>Alejandro Gonzalez</person>
	<person>Aleksey Lim</person>
	<person>Alessandro Decina</person>
	<person>Andoni Morales Alastruey</person>
	<person>Andres Colubri</person>
	<person>André Dieb Martins</person>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Benjamin Gaignard</person>
	<person>Carl-Anton Ingmarsson</person>
	<person>Christian Berentsen</person>
	<person>Damien Lespiau</person>
	<person>David Hoyt</person>
	<person>David Schleef</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Felipe Contreras</person>
	<person>Francis Rammeloo</person>
	<person>Hoseok Chang</person>
	<person>Hu Gang</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Janne Grunau</person>
	<person>Jonathan Rosser</person>
	<person>Josh Doe</person>
	<person>Kaj-Michael Lang</person>
	<person>Karol Sobczak</person>
	<person>Knut Inge Hvidsten</person>
	<person>Lasse Laukkanen</person>
	<person>Leo Singer</person>
	<person>Luciana Fujii Pontello</person>
	<person>Luis de Bethencourt</person>
	<person>Marc-André Lureau</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Mart Raudsepp</person>
	<person>Matthew Ife</person>
	<person>Mike Sheldon</person>
	<person>Noam</person>
	<person>Ole André Vadla Ravnås</person>
	<person>Olivier Aubert</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Rob Clark</person>
	<person>Robert Swain</person>
	<person>Saleem Abdulrasool</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sebastian Pölsterl</person>
	<person>Sreerenj Balachandran</person>
	<person>Stefan Kost</person>
	<person>Teemu Katajisto</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Thijs Vermeir</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Tristan Matthews</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
	<person>Víctor Manuel Jáquez Leal</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>Youness Alaoui</person>
	<person>benjamin gaignard</person>
	<person>kapil</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>628609</id>
      <summary>The qtwrapperaudiodec_samr decoder doesn't handle buffers containing many AMR frames properly</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639296</id>
      <summary>[y4mdec] Doesn't handle files which don't specify a colorspace</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>613379</id>
      <summary>camerabin: Do not use audio clock after stopping video capture</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>636279</id>
      <summary>REGRESSION: Video often freezes during playback of mpeg2 files</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630255</id>
      <summary>[examples] camerabin example still uses old GstXOverlay interface</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631232</id>
      <summary>[colorspace] AYUV/ARGB handling broken on big endian systems</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>627229</id>
      <summary>fpsdisplaysink should not measure fps relative to pipeline clock</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>435120</id>
      <summary>cairosvgoverlay</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>486659</id>
      <summary>xmp/exif metadata handling</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>578629</id>
      <summary>libgstphotography missing exports for MSVC</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>587223</id>
      <summary>mpegtsdemux seg.fault due to invalid PMT_pid</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>598078</id>
      <summary>osxvideosrc doesn't build in snow leopard x86_64</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>600929</id>
      <summary>[kate] tiger element doesn't handle segments and text/video synchronization properly</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>603063</id>
      <summary>camerabin example fails to start recording</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>611428</id>
      <summary>[gdiscreencapsrc] leaks memory (ICONINFO)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>613633</id>
      <summary>[resindvd] scrambled DVDs yield useless generic error message if dvdcss is not available</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>616814</id>
      <summary>Photography interface extension: colour tone mode and noise reduction settings</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>616923</id>
      <summary>camerabin: remove photography interface implementation</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>618045</id>
      <summary>[cogcolorspace] No Y41B support</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>618542</id>
      <summary>DVB subtitles support</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>625558</id>
      <summary>[basevideoencoder] [vp8] encoder timestamps are wrong when there are gaps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>626425</id>
      <summary>cog_virt_frame_new_convert_u8 has bogus source data</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>627134</id>
      <summary>photography interface: add API for capture correction</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>627211</id>
      <summary>jpegformat: Push tags after setting srcpad caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>627253</id>
      <summary>[mpegtsparse] Post tags of channel and currently running event</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>627992</id>
      <summary>dtmfsrc doesn't support gst_element_send_event</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>628326</id>
      <summary>vdpau: don't change structure in setcaps function</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>628527</id>
      <summary>videoanalyse: classificication is wrong</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>628548</id>
      <summary>[mpegtsmux] Initialize PES packet before getting the header size</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>628570</id>
      <summary>cogcolorspace: element classificication is wrong</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>629554</id>
      <summary>dvbsrc: Fix example usage, bandwidth=8 not 8MHz</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>629897</id>
      <summary>[cog] Ignores --disable-orc and always requires orc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>629910</id>
      <summary>jpegparse: properly clean up comment string</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>629917</id>
      <summary>[output-selector] Recheck pending_pad after pushing a buffer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630046</id>
      <summary>sdpdemux: Add optional support for rtspsrc as session element</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630253</id>
      <summary>[sdl] Still uses old GstXOverlay interface</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630254</id>
      <summary>[vdpau] Still uses old GstXOverlay interface</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630783</id>
      <summary>[frei0r] Crashes if broken plugins don't give correct property information</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630808</id>
      <summary>valve: move to core</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631200</id>
      <summary>flacparse: major performance improvements</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631389</id>
      <summary>[flacparse] backport/check corner case fixes done in flacdec</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631449</id>
      <summary>[audioparse] doest not support several channel numbers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631501</id>
      <summary>[faad] failed to dynamically switch from 2 audio channels to 6</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631814</id>
      <summary>[flacparse] unit test failures</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>631993</id>
      <summary>[flacparse] imperfect timestamping</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>632070</id>
      <summary>qtmux: infinite loop</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>632668</id>
      <summary>Gaudi Effects [review]</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>632885</id>
      <summary>Gaudi Effects dynamically controllable parameters [review]</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>632911</id>
      <summary>qtmux: add fragmented mp4 support (isml brand)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>633466</id>
      <summary>[katedec] Pushes events before the final caps are known</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>633917</id>
      <summary>[mpegtsparse] [PATCH] Send TDT messages in an serialized event downstream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635200</id>
      <summary>[dvbbasebin] [PATCH] Add TDT to the initial pids filter for dvbsrc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635202</id>
      <summary>mpeg4videoparse: Minor fixes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635204</id>
      <summary>mpeg4videoparse: Set srcpad caps before forwarding newsegment</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635205</id>
      <summary>h264parse: Set srcpad caps before forwarding newsegment</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635229</id>
      <summary>celtenc: uninitialized tags variable can cause segfault</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635304</id>
      <summary>[opencv] fix caps issues and extend supported caps for some elements [PATCH]</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635397</id>
      <summary>rfbsrc: avoid infinite loop if source gets disconnected and  don't crash if frame geometry changes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635529</id>
      <summary>interlace: Add pattern offset and fix timestamps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635720</id>
      <summary>vp8enc incorrectly sets timestamps based on theoretical framerate</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635786</id>
      <summary>[audioparse] Fix division-by-zero exception</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635878</id>
      <summary>[qtmux] gst_qtmux_check_difference subtract 2 unsigned numbers without taking care of the result sign</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>636106</id>
      <summary>autocolorspace: new plugin for auto space convertor selection</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>636109</id>
      <summary>[SSIM] klass should be Filter/Effect/Video</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>636185</id>
      <summary>qtmux: msvc incompatibility</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637062</id>
      <summary>[ac3parse] parse problems on some MTS streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637224</id>
      <summary>[bayer2rgb] missing framerate in sink caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637308</id>
      <summary>gst-plugins-bad did not find xvidcore on my box</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637359</id>
      <summary>Internal GStreamer error, during pcap to mp4 conversion</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637403</id>
      <summary>qtmux do not store 1st TS when detect 1st buffer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637486</id>
      <summary>qtmux: error if no buffers have arrived to one pad at EOS</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637532</id>
      <summary>applemedia: redundant declaration of 'parent_class'</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637590</id>
      <summary>[PATCH] fix gst-plugins-bad compile against latest gtk+</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637824</id>
      <summary>mpeg4videoparse: gst_buffer_is_metadata_writable warning (regression)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637929</id>
      <summary>mve: do not use the pad buffer allocation functions in demuxers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>637931</id>
      <summary>mpegdemux: do not use the pad buffer allocation functions in demuxers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>638004</id>
      <summary>tiger: fallback on headers in caps to initialize if headers are absent</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>638288</id>
      <summary>qtmux: fails to handle out-of-order buffers without duration</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>638412</id>
      <summary>kate: reenable the sending of a message for tags</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>638527</id>
      <summary>tiger: outline text by default, to make it easier to read</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>638604</id>
      <summary>basecamerasrc isn't build by default but camerabin2 is and requires it</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639063</id>
      <summary>mpegtsparse: fix (re)sync with invalid data at beginning</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639338</id>
      <summary>[qtmux] Protect against copying a null caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639413</id>
      <summary>Camerabin should use output-selector:pad-negotiation-mode=active</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639456</id>
      <summary>[camerabin] Should have all conversion flags enabled by default</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639555</id>
      <summary>[audioparsers] Be careful to not lose the event ref</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>639950</id>
      <summary>flacparse: avoid unref'ing NULL buffer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>630830</id>
      <summary>zbar: Fixes, single frame scan and width/stride fix</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>635281</id>
      <summary>[mpegtsparse] TDT packets are only parsed for odd hours</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
