<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-bad</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Bad Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.12.3</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce the third bugfix release in the stable
1.12 release series of your favourite cross-platform multimedia framework!
</p>
<p>
This release only contains bugfixes and it is safe to update from 1.12.x. For a
full list of bugfixes see <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=VERIFIED&amp;classification=Platform&amp;limit=0&amp;list_id=248880&amp;order=bug_id&amp;product=GStreamer&amp;query_format=advanced&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;target_milestone=1.12.3">Bugzilla</a>.
</p>
<p>
See <a href="&site;/releases/1.12/">&site;/releases/1.12/</a> for the full release notes.
</p>
<p>
<i>"That an accusation?"</i>
</p>
<p>
No perfectly groomed moustache or any amount of fine clothing is going to
cover up the truth - these plugins are Bad with a capital B.
They look fine on the outside, and might even appear to get the job done, but
at the end of the day they're a black sheep. Without a golden-haired angel
to watch over them, they'll probably land in an unmarked grave at the final
showdown.
</p>
<p>
Don't bug us about their quality - exercise your Free Software rights,
patch up the offender and send us the patch on the fastest steed you can
steal from the Confederates. Because you see, in this world, there's two
kinds of people, my friend: those with loaded guns and those who dig.
You dig.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that aren't up to par compared to the
rest.  They might be close to being good quality, but they're missing something
- be it a good code review, some documentation, a set of tests, a real live
maintainer, or some actual wide use.  If the blanks are filled in they might be
upgraded to become part of either gst-plugins-good or gst-plugins-ugly,
depending on the other factors.
If the plugins break, you can't complain - instead, you can fix the
problem and send us a patch, or bribe someone into fixing them for you.
New contributors can start here for things to work on.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
    <contributors>
	<person>Clemens Lang</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>George Kiagiadakis</person>
	<person>Guillaume Desmottes</person>
	<person>Jan Alexander Steffens (heftig)</person>
	<person>Matthew Waters</person>
	<person>Nicola Murino</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Philippe Normand</person>
	<person>Philippe Renon</person>
	<person>Satya Prakash Gupta</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Tom Bailey</person>
	<person>davecraig@unbalancedaudio.com</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>767462</id>
      <summary>gl: cocoa-videooverlay doesn't work</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>782379</id>
      <summary>glimagesink: macOS crash when used with autovideosink</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>784887</id>
      <summary>gsm: Possible Memory leak in gst_buffer_unmap</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>785119</id>
      <summary>mxfdemux: Wrong PTS on some files</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>785941</id>
      <summary>fix flushing seek in rtmpsrc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>785957</id>
      <summary>adaptivedemux: leaks pad probes, causing gradual increase in CPU</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>785987</id>
      <summary>adaptivedemux: Deadlock on stopping pipeline</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>786036</id>
      <summary>vtenc: assume 25 fps for unknown framerate</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>786201</id>
      <summary>player: media-info duration field not updated upon duration-changed signal</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>786250</id>
      <summary>openjpeg: Support libopenjp2 v2.2</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>787234</id>
      <summary>opencv: allow compilation against 3.3.0</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>787309</id>
      <summary>hlsdemux: fix compilation with openssl 1.1.0</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>787442</id>
      <summary>kms: fix crash if bo allocation failed when copying to dumb buffer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>787727</id>
      <summary>player: cosmetic changes</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
