<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-bad</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Bad Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.2.1</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>

<p>
<i>"That an accusation?"</i>
</p>
<p>
No perfectly groomed moustache or any amount of fine clothing is going to
cover up the truth - these plugins are Bad with a capital B.
They look fine on the outside, and might even appear to get the job done, but
at the end of the day they're a black sheep. Without a golden-haired angel
to watch over them, they'll probably land in an unmarked grave at the final
showdown.
</p>
<p>
Don't bug us about their quality - exercise your Free Software rights,
patch up the offender and send us the patch on the fastest steed you can
steal from the Confederates. Because you see, in this world, there's two
kinds of people, my friend: those with loaded guns and those who dig.
You dig.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that aren't up to par compared to the
rest.  They might be close to being good quality, but they're missing something
- be it a good code review, some documentation, a set of tests, a real live
maintainer, or some actual wide use.  If the blanks are filled in they might be
upgraded to become part of either gst-plugins-good or gst-plugins-ugly,
depending on the other factors.
If the plugins break, you can't complain - instead, you can fix the
problem and send us a patch, or bribe someone into fixing them for you.
New contributors can start here for things to work on.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Alex Ashley</person>
	<person>Andoni Morales Alastruey</person>
	<person>Antonio Ospite</person>
	<person>Arnaud Vrac</person>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Brendan Long</person>
	<person>Chen Jie</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Gilles Dartiguelongue</person>
	<person>Greg Rutz</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Matthieu Bouron</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>711627</id>
      <summary>mpegvparse: Incorrect repositioning of start code location when input buffer is empty</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>690148</id>
      <summary>hlsdemux: hangs when network disconnects or when server is unreachable</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707974</id>
      <summary>h264parse: Broken conversion to AVC if a SPS/PPS not from the first indizes is used</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>708161</id>
      <summary>mpegtspacketizer: rework packet extraction and sync</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>708222</id>
      <summary>tsparse: Pushes unparsed data immediately on the srcpad</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>708849</id>
      <summary>hlsdemux: occasionally dereferencing NULL in gst_hls_demux_switch_playlist()</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>709145</id>
      <summary>mpegts: Can't link against mpegts</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>709373</id>
      <summary>camerabin: Filesink not closing file after stop-capture</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>709531</id>
      <summary>egl: Make dependency on egl optional</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>709886</id>
      <summary> &quot; pitch &quot; plugin prevent pipeline creation</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>710392</id>
      <summary>geometrictransform: fix setting black background for AYUV buffers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>710433</id>
      <summary>androidmedia: gst_amc_avc_profile_from_string not recognize alternative profile names</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>710451</id>
      <summary>yadif: OSX linking fails because of unresolved symbols: &quot; pb_1 &quot; and &quot; pw_1 &quot; unreferenced</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>710657</id>
      <summary>avfvideosrc: fix truncated line</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>710881</id>
      <summary>memory leaks in hlsdemux</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>711135</id>
      <summary>applemedia-nonpublic: fix plugin name</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>711156</id>
      <summary>androidmedia: fix access to invalid buffers in the decoding loop</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>711214</id>
      <summary>androidmedia: fix rank for more software decoders</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>711615</id>
      <summary>codecparsers: Condition mistake in h264parser</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>711721</id>
      <summary>mpegvideoparse: Unit test fails</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
