<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-libav</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer libav Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.11.90</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of the
stable 1.12 release series. The 1.12 release series is adding new features on
top of the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8 and 1.10 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Full release notes will be provided with the 1.12.0 release, highlighting all
the new features, bugfixes, performance optimizations and other important
changes.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>

<p>
This module contains plugins based on the ffmpeg project, including codecs.
</p>

<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Emeric Grange</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
  </contributors>

<p>In addition to the above contributors, we would like to extend our
thanks to the ffmpeg developers without which these plugins would have
no reason to exist.</p>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>767938</id>
      <summary>Add support for AVStereo3D API for stereoscopic video</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>780317</id>
      <summary>avvidenc: Classify image encoders with &quot; Image &quot; instead of &quot; Video &quot; </summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
