<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-libav</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer libav Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.5.1</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release of the unstable
1.5 release series. The 1.5 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2 and 1.4 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.5 release series
will lead to the stable 1.6 release series in the next weeks, and newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately
during the unstable 1.5 release series.
</p>

<p>
This module contains plugins based on the libav project, including codecs.
</p>

<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Aleix Conchillo Flaqué</person>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>IBM Thinklab</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Luis de Bethencourt</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>

<p>In addition to the above contributors, we would like to extend our
thanks to the libav developers without which these plugins would have
no reason to exist.</p>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>676131</id>
      <summary>avdec_aac should be ranked above faad</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>726020</id>
      <summary>avdec_h265: freezes when max-threads != 1</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740822</id>
      <summary>av: use GMutex instead of deprecated GStaticMutex</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
