<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.0.2</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>

<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

  <features>
    <feature>Parallel installability with 0.10.x series</feature>
    <feature>alsa: fix probing of supported formats, and advertise non-native-endianness formats as fallback</feature>
    <feature>audiobasesink: properly handle GAP events (fixing some isses with e.g. certain DVD menus)</feature>
    <feature>audioconvert: try harder to not convert or to preserve input format precision</feature>
    <feature>audiodecoder: leak fixes and refcounting fixes</feature>
    <feature>audioresample: re-enable the SSE/SSE2 code paths for better performance</feature>
    <feature>riff: fix paletted RGB formats and msvideo mapping</feature>
    <feature>rtsp: make formatting and parsing of range floating-point values locale-independent</feature>
    <feature>playbin: streamsynchronizer fixes, esp. for handling corner-cases near EOS</feature>
    <feature>tcpserver{sink,src}: add 'current-port' property and signal actually used port</feature>
    <feature>videoconvert: fix handling of paletted RGB formats</feature>
    <feature>videodecoder: don't leak message strings when error is not fatal</feature>
    <feature>videodecoder: finetune missing timestamp estimating</feature>
    <feature>videotestsrc: add palette for paletted RGB formats</feature>
    <feature>vorbistag: fix writing of image tags into vorbis comments</feature>
  </features>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Alexandre Relange</person>
	<person>Andoni Morales Alastruey</person>
	<person>Carlos Rafael Giani</person>
	<person>David Corvoysier</person>
	<person>Josep Torra</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>580093</id>
      <summary>tcpserversink,src: add 'current-port' property and signal actually used port when port=0 was set</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>680904</id>
      <summary>alsasink: no supported formats detected with using USB sound card on big-endian system</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>683098</id>
      <summary>videodecoder: log failure message if acquire_buffer failed</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>684411</id>
      <summary>rtsp: range in SDP formatted according to locale</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>685273</id>
      <summary>Pre-rolling on GAP events doesn't work properly for audio sinks</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>685711</id>
      <summary>audio, video: update docs for virtual functions that require chaining up</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>685938</id>
      <summary>[decodebin] Issues with group switching algorithm</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>686081</id>
      <summary>adder: all unit tests crash now after collectpads changes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>686298</id>
      <summary>Cannot decode some AVI files with Microsoft Video 1</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
