<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.11.2</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.11 release series. The 1.11 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8 and 1.10 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.11 release series
will lead to the stable 1.12 release series in the next weeks. Any newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Full release notes will be provided at some point during the 1.11 release
cycle, highlighting all the new features, bugfixes, performance optimizations
and other important changes.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Carl Karsten</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Georg Lippitsch</person>
	<person>Guillaume Desmottes</person>
	<person>Heekyoung Seo</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Jochen Henneberg</person>
	<person>Olivier Crete</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
	<person>Víctor Manuel Jáquez Leal</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>740557</id>
      <summary>videotestsrc: add ball motion based on system clock</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>775553</id>
      <summary>playback: Fix leak on select_streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>775893</id>
      <summary>decodbin: Leaking pads on errors</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>776797</id>
      <summary>encodebin: fix caps leak in test</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777458</id>
      <summary>decklinkaudiosrc: Option to use max channels supported by device</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777530</id>
      <summary>decodebin3: Fix crash caused by slot double freeing</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778298</id>
      <summary>[REGRESSION]: discoverer: Misunderstands stream topology when a parser does stream formart conversion</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778702</id>
      <summary>videotimecode: Init from GDateTime</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778974</id>
      <summary>video-converter: Implement multi-threaded scaling/conversion</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>779010</id>
      <summary>videotimecode: Validate for drop-frame correctness</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
