<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.3.91</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release candidate of
the stable 1.4 release series. The 1.4 release series is adding new features
on top of the 1.0 and 1.2 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x
release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
This release candidate will hopefully shortly be followed by the stable 1.4.0
release if no bigger regressions or bigger issues are detected, and enough
testing of the release candidate happened. The new API that was added during
the 1.3 release series is not expected to change anymore at this point.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows are provided together with this
release.
</p>
<p>
The stable 1.4 release series is API and ABI compatible with 1.0.x, 1.2.x and
any other 1.x release series in the future. Compared to 1.2.x it contains some
new features and more intrusive changes that were considered too risky as a
bugfix.
</p>

<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Evan Nemerson</person>
	<person>Gwenole Beauchesne</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sebastian Rasmussen</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>730441</id>
      <summary>dmabuf: shared the mapping with shared copies of the memory</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>731974</id>
      <summary>videodecoder: parse source data until a frame is obtained</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732459</id>
      <summary>rtspconnection: tunneled connections do not work if POST channel is established first</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732589</id>
      <summary>gst_mikey_* not introspection-friendly</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732593</id>
      <summary>tests: codec-select: Plug element name memory leak</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732595</id>
      <summary>Introspection and documentation issues for new 1.4 symbols</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732697</id>
      <summary>riff: Hexprint invalid fourcc in error message</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732709</id>
      <summary>sdp: gstmikey.h not included by single include header (sdp.h)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732945</id>
      <summary>giosink: Won't work with mp4mux</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>733046</id>
      <summary>visual: Remove support for &lt; 0.4</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
