<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.4.5</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce a bugfix release of the stable
1.4 release series. The 1.4 release series is adding new features on top
of the 1.2 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework that contains new features.
The 1.4.x bugfix releases only contain important bugfixes compared to 1.4.0.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows are provided by the
GStreamer project for this release.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users. It is not API
or ABI compatible with the 0.10.x series. It can, however, be installed
in parallel with the 0.10.x series and will not affect an existing
0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The stable 1.4.x release series is API and ABI compatible with 1.0.x and
any other 1.x release series in the future. Compared to 1.0.x it contains
some new features and more intrusive changes that were considered too
risky as a bugfix.
</p>

<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Andrei Sarakeev</person>
	<person>Chad</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Göran Jönsson</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Jonathan Matthew</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Peter G. Baum</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Song Bing</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Thomas Klausner</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>William Manley</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>741420</id>
      <summary>video pools: should update size in configuration after applying alignment</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>715050</id>
      <summary>add typefinder for audio/x-audible</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>739544</id>
      <summary>tcp: Add test and fix memory leak in tcp elements</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>739840</id>
      <summary>typefind should recognize Apple Core Audio Format (CAF)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740556</id>
      <summary>videodecoder: don't complain when DTS != PTS on keyframes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740675</id>
      <summary>playsink: continues playback, reset mute property</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740730</id>
      <summary>rtspconnection: don't remove child source if parent source is already destroyed</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740853</id>
      <summary>audiodecoder: Push pending events before sending EOS.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740952</id>
      <summary>alsa: NetBSD fixes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>741045</id>
      <summary>audiorate can can lose timestamp precision in some cases</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>741198</id>
      <summary>playbin: leaks GstPads</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
