<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.5.91</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release candidate for the
stable 1.6 release series. The 1.6 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2 and 1.4 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The final 1.6.0 release is planned
in the next few days unless any major bugs are found.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately by
the GStreamer project.
</p>

<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Carlos Rafael Giani</person>
	<person>Christophe Fergeau</person>
	<person>Eunhae Choi</person>
	<person>George Kiagiadakis</person>
	<person>Havard Graff</person>
	<person>Kouhei Sutou</person>
	<person>Philippe Normand</person>
	<person>Prashant Gotarne</person>
	<person>Ravi Kiran K N</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vikram Fugro</person>
	<person>Vineeth T M</person>
	<person>Vineeth TM</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>734617</id>
      <summary>videodecoder: Call the child class finish() function on stream changes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>740387</id>
      <summary>[REGRESSION] videoscale: The port to the new scaling API broke some file playback</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>744806</id>
      <summary>audiodecoder: early call to drain() causes segment event to be sent before caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>753817</id>
      <summary>subparse: SIGSEGV with abnormal file</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>753850</id>
      <summary>gl: overlay composition negotation with the sink fails</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754199</id>
      <summary>audiobasesink: patch for missing/incorrect documentation about the custom slaving method</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754235</id>
      <summary>playsinkconvertbin: regression after removing accept-caps handler</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754429</id>
      <summary>basetextoverlay: crash in basetextoverlay for padding greater than video size</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754597</id>
      <summary>appsrc: fails to push the caps at the start of the data flow when configured in seekable/random-access mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754630</id>
      <summary>libs: &quot; ll &quot; printf modifier isn't available on MinGW</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754755</id>
      <summary>playbin: Compiler warning with 64bit Windows target MinGW, cast to pointer from integer of different size</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754808</id>
      <summary>video: missing alpha flag for some formats</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>754973</id>
      <summary>xvimagesink: fix error leak when context creation fails</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755098</id>
      <summary>uridecodebin: Smooth Streaming's media type does not match</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755143</id>
      <summary>audiosink, multisocketsink: Fix error leak during failures</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755198</id>
      <summary>basetextoverlay: trivial fix in debug message</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755201</id>
      <summary>playback-test: Dont free null array on exit</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
