<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.6.4</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce a new bug-fix release
in the old 1.6 stable series of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
This release only contains bugfixes and it should be safe to update from 1.6.x.
For a full list of bugfixes see Bugzilla.
</p> 
<p>
This release maintains API/ABI backwards compatibility with the
GStreamer 1.0, 1.2, 1.4 and 1.6 release series.
</p>

<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

      <contributors>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Fabrice Bellet</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Reynaldo H. Verdejo Pinochet</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Tom Deseyn</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>



  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>761257</id>
      <summary>multisocketsink: doesn't handle client close and EWOULDBLOCK</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762239</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: Assertions about unmappable memory when demuxing wavpack streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762710</id>
      <summary>gst_discoverer_info_copy loses some data members of the source GstDiscovererInfo object.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>764020</id>
      <summary>adaptivedemux: Deadlock on HLS and DASH streams when scrub seeking</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693263</id>
      <summary>typefinding: MPEG-2 video ES detected as H.263</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
