<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.7.2</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.7 release series. The 1.7 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4 and 1.6 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.7 release series
will lead to the stable 1.8 release series in the next weeks. Any newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately
during the unstable 1.7 release series.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
    <contributors>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Evan Callaway</person>
	<person>Havard Graff</person>
	<person>HoonHee Lee</person>
	<person>Hugues Fruchet</person>
	<person>Hyunjun Ko</person>
	<person>Julien Isorce</person>
	<person>Koop Mast</person>
	<person>Lubosz Sarnecki</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Nirbheek Chauhan</person>
	<person>Reynaldo H. Verdejo Pinochet</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Stian Selnes</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vineeth T M</person>
	<person>Vineeth TM</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>745880</id>
      <summary>sdp: SDP &lt; - &gt; GstCaps helper functions</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>751901</id>
      <summary>gst-play: verbose &amp; playbin flags options support</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>755918</id>
      <summary>decodebin: Refactor code to remove assertion errors</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>756187</id>
      <summary>appsink: Always blocks on EOS until buffers are consumed since 1.6, should be configurable</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>758212</id>
      <summary>playbin adds the template caps on autoplug-query</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>759729</id>
      <summary>audiofxbad: Name collision with new GstAudioChannelMix API from libgstaudio</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>759855</id>
      <summary>build: pbutils needs to link to libgstbase for bytewriter and adapter</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>759890</id>
      <summary>audioconvert: creates choppy audio</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760134</id>
      <summary>audioconvert test: doesn't build with clang</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760204</id>
      <summary>videotestsrc: add missing break in set_property switch case</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760234</id>
      <summary>playbin: Assumes recursive accept-caps query, breaks totem</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760408</id>
      <summary>#750013 (streamsynchronizer patches) broke some use cases in GES</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760477</id>
      <summary>playbin: caps intersection autoplugs too early and stream stops</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760769</id>
      <summary>tests:audioconvert: Build error when running make check</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760938</id>
      <summary>audioconvert: crash when executing orc unpack function</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>760949</id>
      <summary>decodebin: Correctly expose pads from elements that have directly exposable pads</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761132</id>
      <summary>video-format: fix GstVideoFormatInfo documentation warnings</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761218</id>
      <summary>audio/videodecoder: Use gst_pad_peer_query_caps() instead of using gst_pad_get_allowed_caps() to make negotiated output caps before forwarding GAP event</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761251</id>
      <summary>textoverlay: Expose text rendering dimensions to applications and remove absolute positioning limit</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761949</id>
      <summary>gst-libs/gst/Makefile.am: build audio before rtp</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>761951</id>
      <summary>videoencoder: Fix leak when pre_push does not return OK</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762085</id>
      <summary>gst-base 1.7 update created background buzzing noise with audioconvert</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>762239</id>
      <summary>matroskademux: Assertions about unmappable memory when demuxing wavpack streams</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693263</id>
      <summary>typefinding: MPEG-2 video ES detected as H.263</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
