<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-base</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Base Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.9.90</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of the
stable 1.10 release series. The 1.10 release series is adding new features on
top of the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6 and 1.8 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of reference plugins, base classes for other
plugins, and helper libraries. It also includes essential elements such
as audio and video format converters, and higher-level components like playbin,
decodebin, encodebin, and discoverer.

This module is kept up-to-date together with the core developments.  Element
writers should look at the elements in this module as a reference for
their development.

This module contains elements for, among others:
<ul>
  <li>device plugins: x(v)imagesink, alsa, v4lsrc, cdparanoia</li>
  <li>containers: ogg</li>
  <li>codecs: vorbis, theora</li>
  <li>text: textoverlay, subparse</li>
  <li>sources: audiotestsrc, videotestsrc, giosrc</li>
  <li>network: tcp</li>
  <li>typefind functions</li>
  <li>audio processing: audioconvert, adder, audiorate, audioresample, volume</li>
  <li>visualisation: libvisual</li>
  <li>video processing: videoconvert, videoscale</li>
  <li>high-level components: playbin, uridecodebin, decodebin, encodebin, discoverer</li>
  <li>libraries: app, audio, fft, pbutils, riff, rtp, rtsp, sdp, tag, video</li>
</ul>

Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Havard Graff</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Jonathan Matthew</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
	<person>Víctor Manuel Jáquez Leal</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>Wonchul Lee</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>729276</id>
      <summary>audioresample: Misdetected and/or misused intrinsics headers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>769771</id>
      <summary>rtpbuffer: Add buffer flag RETRANSMISSION</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770314</id>
      <summary>oggdemux: Does not go back to beginning point on EOS when determining stream length</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770446</id>
      <summary>pulsesrc, audiosrc: No audio captured with new GStreamer 1.8.2</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770692</id>
      <summary>playbackutils: Move compare_factories_func</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770698</id>
      <summary>video-orc.orc doesn't compile with orc 0.4.23</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>

</release>
