<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-ugly</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Ugly Plug-ins</module-fancy>
  <name>Run Rabbit</name>
  <version>0.10.14</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new release
in the 0.10.x stable series of the
GStreamer Ugly Plug-ins.
</p>
<p>
The 0.10.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.8.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.8.x series.
</p>

<p>
<i>"When you have to shoot, shoot.  Don't talk."</i>
</p>
<p>
There are times when the world needs a color between black and white.
Quality code to match the good's, but two-timing, backstabbing and ready to
sell your freedom down the river.  These plug-ins might have a patent noose
around their neck, or a lock-up license, or any other problem that makes you
think twice about shipping them.
</p>
<p>
We don't call them ugly because we like them less.  Does a mother love her
son less because he's not as pretty as the other ones ? No  - she commends
him on his great personality.  These plug-ins are the life of the party.
And we'll still step in and set them straight if you report any unacceptable
behaviour - because there are two kinds of people in the world, my friend:
those with a rope around their neck and the people who do the cutting.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plug-ins that have good quality and correct
functionality, but distributing them might pose problems.  The license
on either the plug-ins or the supporting libraries might not be how we'd
like. The code might be widely known to present patent problems.
Distributors should check if they want/can ship these plug-ins.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plug-ins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plug-ins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plug-ins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plug-ins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
<feature>amrwbdec: give decoder a rank so decodebin/playbin will use it</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: fix flow aggregation</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: try harder to put sane timestamps and durations on buffers</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: accept fragments in a continued packet where the subsequent fragments declare a size of 0</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: improve seek behaviour for audio-only files without an index</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: careful to avoid crash on bogus data; avoid strlen() on NULL pointers</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: add support for chained asfs (push mode)</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: map WM/TrackNumber to GST_TAG_TRACK_NUMBER and prefer over WM/Track</feature>
<feature>asfdemux: post bitrate tags</feature>
<feature>mp3parse: seeking fixes: fix non-flushing seek, conserve stop time for non-accurate seek</feature>
<feature>rtspreal: memory leak fixes; make config header construction valgrind clean</feature>
<feature>rmdemux: fix AC-3 in RealAudio playback; post bitrate tags</feature>
<feature>x264enc: fix up avcC header construction and playback by flash players</feature>
<feature>x264enc: Make upstream GstForceKeyUnit thread-safe</feature>
<feature>x264enc: make use of Access Unit delimiters configurable</feature>
<feature>x264enc: adapt to slightly modified x264 API</feature>
<feature>xingmux: fix unaligned memory access, makes things work better on ARM/SPARC</feature>
  </features>

  <applications>
  </applications>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arnaud Patard</person>
	<person>Benjamin Gaignard</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Michael Smith</person>
	<person>Olivier Crête</person>
	<person>Robert Swain</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Stefan Kost</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vittorio Palmisano</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>606662</id>
      <summary>h264: add stream-format to output caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>563276</id>
      <summary>Internal GStreamer error: negotiation problem - after opening avi file</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>586464</id>
      <summary>[xingmux] Unit test failures on sparc and arm/eabi</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>598761</id>
      <summary>[mpegaudioparse] Reduce processing time by 2</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599095</id>
      <summary>x264enc: Adapt to slightly modified x264 API</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599297</id>
      <summary>[asfdemux] Doesn't populate video bitrate field</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599299</id>
      <summary>[rmdemux] Doesn't populate video bitrate field</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599333</id>
      <summary>Segfault with asfdemuxer</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>599676</id>
      <summary>RealAudio file with AC-3 audio no longer plays</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>600037</id>
      <summary>[asfdemux] ASF MPEG4 Part 2 file captured from Linksys WVC200 Camera corrupted/fails</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>601419</id>
      <summary>x264enc crashes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>602280</id>
      <summary>[asfdemux] fix segmentation fault when utf8 tag name is null</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>602556</id>
      <summary>x264enc and ffenc upstream GstForceKeyUnit handling are not thread-safe</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>603695</id>
      <summary>Innaccurate seeking in MP3 files results in cut off playback</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>608564</id>
      <summary>[ffdec_cook] memory leak</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610432</id>
      <summary>[asfdemux] handle negative payload timestamps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>611473</id>
      <summary>[regression] outgoing buffers with a duration of zero</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>608533</id>
      <summary>[real] memory leak in real audio stream via rtsp</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>610089</id>
      <summary>Flash players are unable to show x264 encoded streams</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
