<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-ugly</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Ugly Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.4.1</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce a bugfix release of the stable
1.4 release series. The 1.4 release series is adding new features on top
of the 1.2 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework that contains new features.
The 1.4.x bugfix releases only contain important bugfixes compared to 1.4.0.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows are provided by the
GStreamer project for this release.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users. It is not API
or ABI compatible with the 0.10.x series. It can, however, be installed
in parallel with the 0.10.x series and will not affect an existing
0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The stable 1.4.x release series is API and ABI compatible with 1.0.x and
any other 1.x release series in the future. Compared to 1.0.x it contains
some new features and more intrusive changes that were considered too
risky as a bugfix.
</p>
<p>
<i>"When you have to shoot, shoot.  Don't talk."</i>
</p>
<p>
There are times when the world needs a color between black and white.
Quality code to match the good's, but two-timing, backstabbing and ready to
sell your freedom down the river.  These plugins might have a patent noose
around their neck, or a lock-up license, or any other problem that makes you
think twice about shipping them.
</p>
<p>
We don't call them ugly because we like them less.  Does a mother love her
son less because he's not as pretty as the other ones ? No  - she commends
him on his great personality.  These plugins are the life of the party.
And we'll still step in and set them straight if you report any unacceptable
behaviour - because there are two kinds of people in the world, my friend:
those with a rope around their neck and the people who do the cutting.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that have good quality and correct
functionality, but distributing them might pose problems.  The license
on either the plugins or the supporting libraries might not be how we'd
like. The code might be widely known to present patent problems.
Distributors should check if they want/can ship these plugins.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
  </bugs>
</release>
