<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins-ugly</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Ugly Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.5.1</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release of the unstable
1.5 release series. The 1.5 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2 and 1.4 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.5 release series
will lead to the stable 1.6 release series in the next weeks, and newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately
during the unstable 1.5 release series.
</p>

<p>
<i>"When you have to shoot, shoot.  Don't talk."</i>
</p>
<p>
There are times when the world needs a color between black and white.
Quality code to match the good's, but two-timing, backstabbing and ready to
sell your freedom down the river.  These plugins might have a patent noose
around their neck, or a lock-up license, or any other problem that makes you
think twice about shipping them.
</p>
<p>
We don't call them ugly because we like them less.  Does a mother love her
son less because he's not as pretty as the other ones ? No  - she commends
him on his great personality.  These plugins are the life of the party.
And we'll still step in and set them straight if you report any unacceptable
behaviour - because there are two kinds of people in the world, my friend:
those with a rope around their neck and the people who do the cutting.
</p>
<p>
This module contains a set of plugins that have good quality and correct
functionality, but distributing them might pose problems.  The license
on either the plugins or the supporting libraries might not be how we'd
like. The code might be widely known to present patent problems.
Distributors should check if they want/can ship these plugins.
</p>
<p>
Other modules containing plugins are:

<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
    <feature>Parallel installability with 0.10.x series</feature>
    <feature></feature>
  </features>

<!--
  <applications>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Cliff Han</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Guillaume Desmottes</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Luis de Bethencourt</person>
	<person>Mark Nauwelaerts</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Simon Farnsworth</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vincent Penquerc'h</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>731351</id>
      <summary>x264enc: Shift PTS and DTS with bframes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>453322</id>
      <summary>dvdreadsrc ignores chapter specification when starting playback</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>734471</id>
      <summary>asfdemux: Should pass seek events upstream first</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>735070</id>
      <summary>asfdemux: ASF file with H.264 video not playing back properly</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>735379</id>
      <summary>mpeg2dec: use stride information from GstVideoFrame</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>737516</id>
      <summary>gst-launch-1.0 videotestsrc ! x264enc ! decodebin ! autovideosink doesn't want to preroll</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>746781</id>
      <summary>a52dec: audio noise/distortions when there are multiple AC-3 streams being decoded in parallel</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>746887</id>
      <summary>mpeg2dec: fix a couple of leaks</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>748162</id>
      <summary>asfdemux: can't seek to the offset which is bigger than 4G bytes in push mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>732288</id>
      <summary>x264enc: Does not request enough buffers in allocation query</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
