<?xml-stylesheet href="tasks.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Tasks</title>
  <body>
  </body>
  
  <tasks title="List of GNOME-related tasks">

    <task name="fontselection">
      <title>Add font selection for subtitles in Totem</title>
      <description>
        Since some time now, <xref type="http"
        linkend="http://hadess.net/totem.php3">Totem</xref> (using the GStreamer
        backend) has had subtitle support from Ogm or Matroska streams or
        from external subtitle files. What's lacking, though, is font
        selection in the Totem user interface.
      </description>
      <why>
        It'd be nice if users could select their own font type, size and
        color using a font selector widget in the Totem preferences screen.
        This fits in well with the GNOME philosophy where user interfaces
        are simple and intuitive.
      </why>
      <how>
        The preferences dialog of Totem is defined in the glade file
        <filename>totem.glade</filename> (in <filename>totem/data/</filename>).
        Here, you can add an additional notebook page for font handling. Add
        useful descriptions on what it does. Next, you'll need to add signal
        handlers in <filename>totem/src/totem.c</filename>, and add function
        calls to the <classname>BaconVideoWidget</classname> backend.
        <br/>
        In <application>GStreamer</application>, font-selection is done in
        the textoverlay element (in
        <filename>gst-plugins/ext/pango/gsttextoverlay.c</filename>) using the
        <quote>font-desc</quote> property. Add a similar property to the
        playbin element (which is the playback backend for Totem), and make
        the <classname>BaconVideoWidget</classname> in Totem use this
        property to set the font. Lastly, choose a nice default (something
        like Vera bitstream) and make this property work using GConf as well.
      </how>
      <where>
        <code id="totem">
          <name>Totem</name>
          <description>The totem module in GNOME CVS.</description>
        </code>
        <code id="playbin">
          <name>playbin</name>
          <description>The playbin element in GStreamer CVS, module
          <quote>gst-plugins</quote>.</description>
        </code>
      </where>
      <difficulty>
        EASY - font selection in Gtk+ is well documented, and it requires
        little code in both Totem and playbin.
      </difficulty>
      <notes>
        Any questions about this task should be sent to the gnome-media
        mailing list.
      </notes>
      <see>
        <person>Ronald</person>
        <person>Bastien</person>
      </see>
    </task>
    
  <task name="propdocs">
      <title>Create online docs for Profile manager</title>
      <description>
  	There is a new tool for setting values for audio encoding bitrates as such called gnome-audio-profiles-properties. This tools is meant to be called from relevant applications. But it needs to have its own online docs added</description>
  
      <why>
  	All GNOME applications should have online documentation and this being a poweruser feature definetly needs it.
      </why>
  
      <how>
  	Look at gnome-sound-recorder or any other GNOME module with online docs to see how they are done. You should also look over the GNOME Documentation project for information on how to do this.</how>
  
      <where>
        <code id="grecord">
          <name>grecord</name>
          <description>The code of gnome-sound-recorder which can serve as an example</description>
        </code>
        
      </where>
  
      <difficulty>
        EASY - Many examples to look at.
      </difficulty>
      <submit>
        Patch should be made against gnome-media CVS and sent it ot the gnome-multimedia mailing list.
      </submit>
      <notes>
  Any questions about this task should be sent to the gnome-media mailing list.
      </notes>
      <see>
        <person>Ted Gould</person>
      </see>
    </task>
  
    <task name="libgnomeify">
      <title>Update and merge libgnome GStreamer patches</title>
      <description>
  	There where a couple of patches made long ago that migrates libgnome to use GStreamer for audio playback. These patches should be cleaned up (use GStreamer directly) and verified to work with GStreamer 0.7/0.8.
  	</description>
  
      <why>
  	As we are now moving to really take advantage of GStreamer in the GNOME technology stack it is natural to also move libgnome to GStreamer.</why>
  
      <how>
  	Patches can be found in these two GNOME bugzilla entries <A HREF="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=82340">82340</A> and <A HREF="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=82341">82341</A>. These patches uses monkey-media. Today we probably want to access GStreamer directly or use gstplay.</how>
  
	<where>
        <code id="libgnome">
          <name>GNOME development library</name>
          <description>GNOME development library</description>
        </code>
        <code id="libgnomeui">
          <name>GNOME UI development library</name>
          <description>GNOME UI development library</description>
        </code>

      </where>
      <difficulty>
        MEDIUM - Fairly simple code, but at a very high impact place in the toolchain.
      </difficulty>
      <submit>
        Patch should be made against libgnome and libgnomeui CVS and sent to the gnome-desktop mailing list.
      </submit>
      <notes>
  Any questions about this task should be sent to the gnome-media mailing list.
      </notes>
      <see>
        <person>Thomas</person>
        <person>Anders</person>
      </see>
    </task>
   
   <task name="mediacaching">
      <title>Design and implement media info caching</title>
      <description>
  	We want a system similar to the image thumbnail standard on freedesktop.org for caching metadata. That way every application do not need to cache this for themselves.
  	</description>
  
      <why>
  	That way every application do not need to cache this for themselves.</why>
  
      <how>
  	Look at the <A HREF="http://triq.net/~jens/thumbnail-spec/index.html">thumbnail standard</A> for some design ideas.</how>
  
      <difficulty>
        HARD - Needs good design and implementation skills, along with patience with working with large groups of people.
      </difficulty>
      <submit>
        Proposal should be sent to freedesktop. Implementation patches to relevant modules.
      </submit>
      <notes>
  Any questions about this task should be sent to the gnome-media mailing list.
      </notes>
      <see>
        <person>Thomas</person>
      </see>
    </task>
  
  </tasks>
</page>
