<?xml-stylesheet href="tasks.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
  <title>GStreamer: Tasks</title>
  <body>
  </body>

  <tasks title="List of GStreamer tasks">

    <task name="subtitles">
      <title>Add more subtitle formats to GStreamer</title>
      <description>
        For some time now, <application>GStreamer</application> has supported
        subtitles. One of the players using this feature is <xref type="http"
        linkend="http://hadess.net/totem.php3">Totem</xref>. Subtitles are
        automatically supported if you use the <classname>playbin</classname>
        element. Currently, Ogm and Matroska plain-text subtitles and external
        subtitle files in microDVD, MPsub and Subrip format are supported.
        It would be nice to support more types of subtitles, particularly the
        ones in external text files, since those are very easy to add.
      </description>
      <why>
        It's a good idea to support as many media formats as possible. In
        addition, our subtitle support is not very wide yet, and we hope
        to change that.
      </why>
      <how>
        External subtitle files are handled by the <quote>subparse</quote>
        element (in
        <filename>gst-plugins/gst/subparse/gstsubparse.c</filename>). Each
        subtitle has three functions available - one for initialization, one
        for reading a single subtitle and one to deinitialize. For each new
        subtitle format, adding those three functions is enough. After that,
        test the newly added code in Totem. If all is well, it should just
        work.
        <br/>
        It is also possible to add more subtitle support to particular
        demuxers, e.g. Ogg/Ogm or Matroska. In that case look at the code
        of that particular demuxer and it there.
      </how>
      <where>
        <code id="subparse">
          <name>subparse</name>
          <description>The subparse element in the gst-plugins module in
          GStreamer CVS.</description>
        </code>
      </where>
      <difficulty>
        EASY: three functions per format, and no code involved elsewhere.
      </difficulty>
      <see>
        <person>Ronald</person>
        <person>Thomas</person>
      </see>
    </task>
   </tasks>
</page>

