<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name>Wooden Eels</name>
  <version>0.7.4</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is happy to announce a new release in the
0.7.x development series of the GStreamer streaming-media framework.
The goal of this release series is to stabilize towards a 0.8
release series which will be part of the GNOME 2.6 releases
and hopefully eventually KDE 4.x. 
</p>
<p>
The 0.7 series is a development series and is aimed at developers.
It is NOT API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.6.x series or
with other releases in the series.  This means you can not use this
release to upgrade your current GStreamer installation and expect your
GStreamer applications to keep working without a recompile.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.6.x series.
</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
    <feature>Merged the new caps system</feature>
    <feature>Reworked pad negotiation</feature>
    <feature>Internationalized core and elements</feature>
    <feature>Reworked error notification with translated error messages and additional debug information for developer feedback</feature>
    <feature>Updated Dutch and French translations</feature>
    <feature>Reworked clocking</feature>
    <feature>Serialization of GstValue</feature>
    <feature>Documentation of GstCaps</feature>
    <feature>Poisoning of GstCaps</feature>
    <feature>Queues now flushed properly to fix seeking in playback</feature>
    <feature>Memleak fixes in core elements</feature>
    <feature>Largely rewritten Plugin Writer's Guide</feature>
    <feature>Unversioned tools that wrap all present and future versioned tools to help packagers</feature>
    <feature>Lots of bugfixes</feature>
  </features>

  <applications>
<p>
As mentioned there are some changes in API/ABI between the 0.6.x and 0.7.x
releases.
Many applications will probably be source compatible between 0.6.x. and 0.7.x
however.
<a href="http://www.rhythmbox.org/">Rhythmbox</a> and
<a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">Sound Juicer</a>
for instance work very well when compiled on 0.7.x.
GStreamer Player does not work across releases however,
so we will make a separate release of gst-player with the needed
fixes for it to work with 0.7.x. This release contains the core fixes we
were waiting for to port the player over so expect a gst-player release in
the near future.
</p>
  </applications>
  <contributors>
    <person>David Schleef</person>
    <person>Benjamin Otte</person>
    <person>Thomas Vander Stichele</person>
    <person>Iain Holmes</person>
    <person>Ronald Bultje</person>
    <person>Colin Walters</person>
    <person>Jan Schmidt</person>
    <person>Jérémy Simon</person>
    <person>Leif Morgan Johnson</person>
    <person>Julien Moutte</person>
    <person>Jon Trowbridge</person>
    <person>Christian Fredrik Kalager Schaller</person>
    <person>Laurent Vivier</person>
  </contributors>
</release>
