<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.0.6</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series has been reworked for more flexible memory handling, improved
caps negotiation and re-negotiation, better handling of dynamic pipelines,
and increased performance in general. It also features countless other feature
additions and enhancements.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

  <features>
    <feature>bin: reset GValue from iterator after usage, fixing leak</feature>
    <feature>pipeline: fix seeking on pipeline with NULL clock</feature>
    <feature>message: accept NULL error argument in gst_message_parse_{error,warning,info}</feature>
    <feature>basesrc: handle renegotiation correctly</feature>
    <feature>basesink: handle sync of EOS after item without duration</feature>
    <feature>basetransform: avoid warnings from NULL outcaps passed to transform_size in shutdown race</feature>
    <feature>adapter, basesrc, typefind: handle gst_buffer_map failure</feature>
    <feature>queuearray: fix gst_queue_array_drop_element()</feature>
    <feature>queuearray: fix gst_queue_array_find()</feature>
    <feature>queue: remove query from queue if queue is flushing</feature>
    <feature>g-i: make sure enumeration types and flags are introspected and available to bindings</feature>
    <feature>g-i: add allow-none annotation for gst_pipeline_new()'s name property</feature>
  </features>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Alexander Schrab</person>
	<person>Nate Bogdanowicz</person>
	<person>Niv Sardi</person>
	<person>Simon Feltman</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Tim 'mithro' Ansell</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->



  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>684804</id>
      <summary>basesink: fails to post EOS message with RTSP stream</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>691185</id>
      <summary>g-i: GStreamer enums and flags not usable - &quot; expected enumeration type GstFormat, but got Format instead &quot; warning when setting GstFormat property on GStreamer appsrc element</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>691985</id>
      <summary>gst_pad_check_reconfigure: only remove flag if set.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>691986</id>
      <summary>basesrc: set NEED_RECONFIGURE flag if negotiate fails</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>692691</id>
      <summary>queue: dangling pointer when doing allocation query on a flushing queue</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>692868</id>
      <summary>basesink: expands GAP event without duration to last to segment end</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693065</id>
      <summary>pipeline: criticals when seeking on pipeline with NULL clock</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693587</id>
      <summary>Adding offset to GstSegment deserialize/serialize to fix jump on uninitialized value</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693704</id>
      <summary>gst_message_parse_{warning,error} annotations wrongly claim allow-none for GError parameter</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>693996</id>
      <summary>basetransform: audioresample shutdown unit test fails with 'gst_audio_info_from_caps: caps != NULL'  in transform_size</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
