<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.1.90</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series has been reworked for more flexible memory handling, improved
caps negotiation and re-negotiation, better handling of dynamic pipelines,
and increased performance in general. It also features countless other feature
additions and enhancements.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Christian Fredrik Kalager Schaller</person>
	<person>Gustavo Noronha Silva</person>
	<person>Jonas Holmberg</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Mathieu Duponchelle</person>
	<person>Rico Tzschichholz</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sebastian Rasmussen</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Zaheer Abbas Merali</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>701996</id>
      <summary>context: Still inconvenient to use and racy</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707088</id>
      <summary>capsfilter: Don't forget to update pending_events.</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707130</id>
      <summary>output-selector: Changes the start of the segment it sends to a pad when making it active</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707156</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: Lowering single queue limits below automatically detected limits can cause the pipeline to starve</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707648</id>
      <summary>queue2: Update the buffering state before stalling for more data</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>707657</id>
      <summary>tests/capsfilter: Improving check test code coverage...</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
