<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.11.2</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.11 release series. The 1.11 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8 and 1.10 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.11 release series
will lead to the stable 1.12 release series in the next weeks. Any newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>
<p>
Full release notes will be provided at some point during the 1.11 release
cycle, highlighting all the new features, bugfixes, performance optimizations
and other important changes.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Brendan Shanks</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Julien Isorce</person>
	<person>Nirbheek Chauhan</person>
	<person>Peter Korsgaard</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Seungha Yang</person>
	<person>Stefan Sauer</person>
	<person>Stian Selnes</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Vivia Nikolaidou</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>764707</id>
      <summary>segment: Modifiy inside segment condition</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>773091</id>
      <summary>check: Add API to filter g_warning/g_critical etc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777375</id>
      <summary>paramspec: Add gst_param_spec_array_list for GST_TYPE_ARRAY</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777449</id>
      <summary>parse: Deadlock when trying to link an element that takes its object lock while querying caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777780</id>
      <summary>GstBaseParse incorrectly handles non-flush seek</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>777810</id>
      <summary>GstStream and GstStreamCollection missing g_autoptr() support</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>778866</id>
      <summary>gstconfig.h.in: Fix unaligned access support for the openrisc architecture</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
