<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.2.3</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is proud to announce a new bug-fix release
in the 1.x stable series of the
core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users.
It is not API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.10.x series.
It is, however, parallel installable with the 0.10.x series and
will not affect an existing 0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series has been reworked for more flexible memory handling, improved
caps negotiation and re-negotiation, better handling of dynamic pipelines,
and increased performance in general. It also features countless other feature
additions and enhancements.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Arnaud Vrac</person>
	<person>Pedro Côrte-Real</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sebastian Rasmussen</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>YanpingZhang</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>712597</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: regression: buffering of live radio stream never finishes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>719814</id>
      <summary>docs: add missing files for distribution</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721253</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: May cause hanging if shut down while handling a serialized query</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721289</id>
      <summary>pad: using multiple blocking probes doesn't work as expected</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721300</id>
      <summary>tee: Does not protect pad from being destroyed from pad probe during gst_pad_push()</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721350</id>
      <summary>baseparse: push pending events before GAP</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721422</id>
      <summary>Negative pad offsets don't work</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>721941</id>
      <summary>baseparse: do not accumulate buffers on passthrough mode</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>722467</id>
      <summary>pad: Leaks events when iterating sticky events and callback drops event</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
