<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.3.2</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the second release of the unstable
1.3 release series. The 1.3 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0 and 1.2 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework. The unstable 1.3 release series
will lead to the stable 1.4 release series in the next weeks, and newly added
API can still change until that point.
</p>

<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided separately
during the unstable 1.3 release series.
</p>

<p>
The versioning scheme that is used in general is that 1.x.y is API and
ABI backwards compatible with previous 1.x.y releases. If x is an even
number it is a stable release series and all releases in this series
will only contain important bugfixes, e.g. the 1.0 series with 1.0.7. If
x is odd it is a development release series that will lead to the next
stable release series 1.x+1 and contains new features and bigger
changes. During the development release series, new API can still
change.
</p>

<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Nicolas Dufresne</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>Руслан Ижбулатов</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>726423</id>
      <summary>playbin/decodebin: aggregate buffering messages</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>680183</id>
      <summary>queue2: when download buffering has holes, plug the holes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>727916</id>
      <summary>bufferpool: Does not implement set_config() as documented</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>728268</id>
      <summary>Need a way to detect that pool haven't changed, is active, and does not need to be renegotiated</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>729949</id>
      <summary>core plugins and libgstbase now depend on gio</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>729951</id>
      <summary>base: keep new GstSparseFile helper API private</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>730125</id>
      <summary>c7d68da broke W32 builds</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>730312</id>
      <summary>Remove or fix reference to Mandrake</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
