<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.4.0</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release of
the stable 1.4 release series. The 1.4 release series is adding new
features on top of the 1.0 and 1.2 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>

<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows are provided together
with this release.
</p>

<p>
The stable 1.4 release series is API and ABI compatible with 1.0.x,
1.2.x and any other 1.x release series in the future. Compared to 1.2.x
it contains some new features and more intrusive changes that were
considered too risky as a bugfix.
</p>

<p>
The versioning scheme that is used in general is that 1.x.y is API and
ABI backwards compatible with previous 1.x.y releases. If x is an even
number it is a stable release series and all releases in this series
will only contain important bugfixes, e.g. the 1.0 series with 1.0.7. If
x is odd it is a development release series that will lead to the next
stable release series 1.x+1 and contains new features and bigger
changes. During the development release series, new API can still
change.
</p>

<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

    <contributors>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Sebastian Rasmussen</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>733121</id>
      <summary>debugutils: Unref pad template after use</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>733291</id>
      <summary>typefindelement: Propagate input buffer PTS and DTS</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
