<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.4.4</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce a bugfix release of the stable
1.4 release series. The 1.4 release series is adding new features on top
of the 1.2 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x release
series of the GStreamer multimedia framework that contains new features.
The 1.4.x bugfix releases only contain important bugfixes compared to 1.4.0.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows are provided by the
GStreamer project for this release.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series is a stable series targeted at end users. It is not API
or ABI compatible with the 0.10.x series. It can, however, be installed
in parallel with the 0.10.x series and will not affect an existing
0.10.x installation.
</p>
<p>
The stable 1.4.x release series is API and ABI compatible with 1.0.x and
any other 1.x release series in the future. Compared to 1.0.x it contains
some new features and more intrusive changes that were considered too
risky as a bugfix.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

<!--
  <applications>
<p>
Applications ported to GStreamer 1.0 include Totem, RhythmBox, Sound-Juicer,
Pitivi, Cheese, Empathy, Transmageddon, and others.
</p>
  </applications>
-->

      <contributors>
	<person>Aleix Conchillo Flaqué</person>
	<person>Andrei Sarakeev</person>
	<person>Guillaume Desmottes</person>
	<person>Matej Knopp</person>
	<person>Nicolas Huet</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>

<!--
  <api>
    <additions>
    </additions>
    <deprecations>
    </deprecations>
  </api>
-->

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>737498</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: doesn't take GAP event into account when calculating current level</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>737794</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: deadlock if queue overruns with serialized events</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>737999</id>
      <summary>systemclock: multi-thread entry status issue</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>738198</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: Does not wake up not-linked streams on EOS</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
