<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.6.4</version>

  <intro>

<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce a new bug-fix release in the
old 1.6 stable series of the core of the GStreamer streaming media framework.
</p>
<p>
This release only contains bugfixes and it should be safe to update from 1.6.x.
For a full list of bugfixes see Bugzilla.
</p> 
<p>
This release maintains API/ABI backwards compatibility with the
GStreamer 1.0, 1.2, 1.4 and 1.6 release series.
</p>
<p>
The 1.x series has been reworked for more flexible memory handling, improved
caps negotiation and re-negotiation, better handling of dynamic pipelines,
and increased performance in general. It also features countless other feature
additions and enhancements.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

  <features>
  </features>

            <contributors>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Ben Iofel</person>
	<person>Edward Hervey</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Romain Picard</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
  </contributors>



  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>759539</id>
      <summary>Stopping a stream with AAC very soon after starting crashes</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763491</id>
      <summary>typefind: behavior has changed on have-type signal, sets pad caps after signal handlers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763895</id>
      <summary>Incorrect gir annotation on gst_element_query_convert</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763912</id>
      <summary>pad/utils: missing annotation for gst_pad_get_current_caps and gst_pad_peer_query_caps</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763770</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: not-linked pads might not drain out at EOS</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
