<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.8.0</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release of the new stable
1.8 release series. The 1.8 release series is adding new features on top of
the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4 and 1.6 series and is part of the API and ABI-stable 1.x
release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided shortly after
the source release by the GStreamer project during the stable 1.8 release
series.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>
    <contributors>
	<person>Anthony G. Basile</person>
	<person>Aurélien Zanelli</person>
	<person>Ben Iofel</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Romain Picard</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>763491</id>
      <summary>typefind: behavior has changed on have-type signal, sets pad caps after signal handlers</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763895</id>
      <summary>Incorrect gir annotation on gst_element_query_convert</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>764034</id>
      <summary>preset: Use GST_PRESET_PATH as an extension of the system path, not a replacement of the user path</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>763770</id>
      <summary>multiqueue: not-linked pads might not drain out at EOS</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
