<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml [ <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../../entities.site"> %site-entities; ]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gstreamer</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer</module-fancy>
  <name></name>
  <version>1.9.90</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of the
stable 1.10 release series. The 1.10 release series is adding new features on
top of the 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, 1.6 and 1.8 series and is part of the API and
ABI-stable 1.x release series of the GStreamer multimedia framework.
</p>
<p>
Binaries for Android, iOS, Mac OS X and Windows will be provided in the next days.
</p>
<p>
This module, gstreamer, only contains core functionality.
For actual media playback, you will need other modules.
<dl>
<dt>gst-plugins-base</dt>
<dd>contains a basic set of well-supported plugins</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-good</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins under our preferred license</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-ugly</dt>
<dd>contains a set of well-supported plugins, but might pose problems for
    distributors</dd>
<dt>gst-plugins-bad</dt>
<dd>contains a set of less supported plugins that haven't passed the
    rigorous quality testing we expect, or are still missing documentation
    and/or unit tests</dd>
<dt>gst-libav</dt>
<dd>contains a set of codecs plugins based on libav (formerly gst-ffmpeg)</dd>
</dl>

</p>
  </intro>

    <contributors>
	<person>Arun Raghavan</person>
	<person>Carlos Rafael Giani</person>
	<person>Graham Leggett</person>
	<person>Jan Schmidt</person>
	<person>Kouhei Sutou</person>
	<person>Nirbheek Chauhan</person>
	<person>Sebastian Dröge</person>
	<person>Thiago Santos</person>
	<person>Thibault Saunier</person>
	<person>Tim-Philipp Müller</person>
	<person>Wim Taymans</person>
	<person>Wonchul Lee</person>
  </contributors>

  <bugs>
    <bug>
      <id>753922</id>
      <summary>GValue types are registered after types that might use them (e.g. tags)</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770731</id>
      <summary>gstconfig.h: Need to add support for more platforms / PPC broken</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>770740</id>
      <summary>No way to disable build of tests/misc</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771104</id>
      <summary>element: seek_simple() does not reset stop position</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771210</id>
      <summary>tests: new queue2: Add higher-resolution low/high-watermark properties unit test is flaky</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771306</id>
      <summary>basesink: Remove unused fields and always use the buffer timestamp difference for calculating the QoS proportion</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771649</id>
      <summary>gst_bin_sort_iterator_copy doesn't copy GstBinSortIterator::queue</summary>
    </bug>
    <bug>
      <id>771029</id>
      <summary>MSVC can't link against autotools-build generated DLLs</summary>
    </bug>
  </bugs>
</release>
