<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../releases.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<release>
  <module>gst-plugins</module>
  <module-fancy>GStreamer Plugins</module-fancy>
  <name>Mobil Avenue</name>
  <version>0.7.3</version>

  <intro>
<p>
The GStreamer team is happy to announce a new release in the
0.7.x development series of the GStreamer streaming-media framework.
The goal of this release series is to stabilize it towards a 0.8
release series which will be part of the GNOME 2.6 releases
and hopefully eventually KDE 4.x. 
</p>
<p>
The 0.7 series is a development series and is aimed at developers.
It is NOT API or ABI compatible with the stable 0.6.x series or
with other releases in the series.  This means you can not use this
release to upgrade your current GStreamer installation and expect your
GStreamer applications to keep working without a recompile.
It is however parallel installable with the 0.6.x series.
</p>
  </intro>
  <features>
    <feature>Support for playback of WMA files</feature>
    <feature>Support for playback of AAC files</feature>
    <feature>Support for playback of Quicktime using Sorensen 1</feature>
    <feature>Stabilizing playback library</feature>
    <feature>gst-register handles broken plug-ins gracefully</feature>
    <feature>New Real Demuxer (no decoder yet)</feature>
    <feature>Support for playing some WMV files (needs more work)</feature>
    <feature>Improved C based Matroska plugin</feature>
    <feature>New specialized ximage and xvimage plugins for non-xv and xv X windows systems</feature>
  </features>

  <applications>
<p>
As mentioned there are some changes in API/ABI between the 0.6.x and 0.7.x
releases.
Many applications will probably be source compatible between 0.6.x. and 0.7.x
however.
<a href="http://www.rhythmbox.org/">Rhythmbox</a> and
<a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">Sound Juicer</a>
for instance work very well when compiled on 0.7.x.
GStreamer Player does not work accross releases however,
so we will make a separate release of gst-player with the needed
fixes for it to work with 0.7.x. This release contains the core fixes we
were waiting for to port the player over so expect a gst-player release in
the near future.
</p>
  </applications>
  <contributors>
    <person>David Schleef</person>
    <person>Andy Wingo</person>
    <person>Julien Moutte</person>
    <person>Ronald Bultje</person>
    <person>Iain Holmes</person>
    <person>Jérémy Simon</person>
    <person>Leif Morgan Johnson</person>
    <person>Benjamin Otte</person>
    <person>Thomas Vander Stichele</person>
    <person>Christian Fredrik Kalager Schaller</person>
  </contributors>
</release>
