<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>

<?xml-stylesheet href="../page.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<page>
<head>
  <title>GStreamer Google Summer of Code 2015</title>
</head>
<body>

<h1>GStreamer Google Summer of Code 2015</h1>

<p>
Welcome to the GStreamer Google Summer of Code 2015.
</p>
<p>
Google Summer of Code is a program run by Google in collaboration with various open source projects. The goal of the program is to allow students to work on open source software during their summer break and gain valuable experience and skills. Google has been running the program for many years now and many students have gained valuable experience and skills doing GStreamer related Summer of Code. These pages will provide you with some general information about how to apply, some ideas we have, how to pitch your own ideas and how to write a GSoC application that is likely to get accepted.
</p>
<p>
These pages outline the requirements and ideas for participating in the Google Summer of code doing a
project around GStreamer. In addition to any requests we have you also need to qualify according to the
guidelines provided by Google. So recommend that if you haven't already done so, take a look at <a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/homepage/google/gsoc2015">the Google Summer of Code</a> information on the Google website. You also need to apply through that site.
</p>
<p>
Once you done that what you want to do is to look over our general information page for students. It contains hints and tips for how you can write a proposal that we are likely to approve.
<a href="studentinfo.html">You will find our general information page here.</a>
</p>
<p>
Once you have done that you can browse through our project ideas page. Remember you can always choose to submit your own idea even if its not on the ideas page, just be sure to talk to us first to make sure we have someone who can mentor you. You find <a href="socprojects.html">the project ideas page here</a>.
</p>
<p>
Finally make sure to join the #gstreamer IRC channel on irc.oftc.net as soon as you can. It is where all the main GStreamer developers hang out, including your future Summer of Code mentor. Asking questions there and participating in the community is a great way to improve your chances of being chosen.
</p>
</body>
</page>
