<!DOCTYPE xsl:stylesheet
[
  <!ENTITY % site-entities SYSTEM "../entities.site">
  %site-entities;
]>
<status>
  <item>
    <title>GStreamer status, 20 Sept 2005</title>
    <date>2005-09-20 00:00</date>
    <content>
<pre>
Aloha hackers,

This is the first installment of what I hope will be a weekly or
biweekly newsletter on the state of GStreamer. You will find in it a
discussion of recent API changes, bug and release status, and notes on a
featured application built with GStreamer. I hope you enjoy this first
one. Let me know what you think about it, good or bad, and especially
let me know if you want to write a paragraph or so about your area of
GStreamer interest.


Recent Core Changes
-------------------

The registry recently underwent a rewrite at the hands of David Scheef.
Developers will notice that there are no more pluggable registries or
registry pools, and that some of the plugin/pluginfeature semantics have
changed. Users will notice that there is no more gst-register. Initial
reports show this registry to be faster at rebuilding than the old one
and that run-time rebuilding actually works. Someone should port the
gnome-multimedia utilities to 0.9 to see how the changes affect Gnome
startup time :-)

Also, Wim Taymans checked in some bus-related changes. What was called a
GstBusHandler is now a GstBusFunc, to match the naming of GSourceFunc,
and its return value is just like any other GSourceFunc -- that is, TRUE
to keep the source in the GMainContext, and FALSE otherwise. Also, now
you can attach multiple bus watches, each listening to a different set
of events. A related change is that gst_bus_poll now returns the actual
message that was received, not just its type -- no need to explicitly
pop the message off the bus anymore.

In other changes, Stefan Kost checked in a patch to use GLib 2.8's
atomic refcounting for GObject, which was something Wim pushed hard for
in GLib's last development cycle. Of course, we still support the hacks
that allow GStreamer to work reliably with GLib as old as 2.4, but you
have to be careful when getting an object from GLib, as with
g_value_get_object.

David also recently removed our atomic memchunk and trash stack
implementations, which is related to ongoing work in GLib -- see
http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=118439. This change shouldn't
affect anyone out there.

Thomas on the other hand has continued on his masochistic selfless quest
for quality, adding a 'make valgrind' target to the build. He will be
rewarded in heaven.


Buildbot status
---------------

The buildbot configuration has been partly upgraded for some slaves to
build the new modules. The Mac OSX buildslave is on a short holiday
while it's being upgraded. The Fedora Core 4 slave will now be
valgrinding and reporting leaks as failures.

Remember - if you're not part of the solution, you're part of the
problem ! Buildbot will still blame you if you keep committing to a tree
that's in a broken state. So hold off committing if the tree is broken
and you're not trying to fix it yourself.

We are still looking for more build slave platforms to add to our
system.  In particular, a Windows slave would be great.


Meanwhile, Back At The Ranch
----------------------------

Or, notable activity in the plugins modules. Have you checked out the
plugins documentation[1]? Go and see it and then tell Thomas how awesome
he is. The goal here is to have every element come with either an
example launch line or a small program that demonstrates the use of the
element. This is a very simple thing for new developers to be
contributing to and it helps in understanding how GStreamer works.

gst-plugins-base: Leak fixing, a new RTP payloader base class, 24 bit
audioconvert

gst-plugins-good: Work on RTP payloaders (AMR, GSM, H263, MP4, MPA),
wavparse updates

gst-plugins-bad: A ported SDL video sink, yay

gst-plugins-ugly: lame updates, documentation work

[1] http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/documentation/plugins.html


Bug Activity
------------

Total number of GStreamer bugs as of today : 200
Number opened in the last week             : +21
Number closed in the last week             : -22
Net change                                 : -1

GStreamer is currently number 9 on the list of projects with the most
bugs in GNOME bugzilla. Our project is a pile of bugs!

Luca Ognibene has put together a triaged list of bugs for the stable
series (0.8) here[2]. Some of these are low-hanging fruit, and it's an
easy-to-read list -- check it out if you have half an hour free
sometime.

[2] http://skaboy.no-ip.org/~luogni/gst08-bug-status-20050919


Featured Application: Banshee
-----------------------------

Christian Schaller lets us know about this week's featured application.

A lot of application development is being done using Mono and C# these
days and Banshee is no exception. Banshee is a music player being
developed with the support of Novell with a interface similar to what
you find in applications such as iTunes and Rhythmbox. Banshee is has a
lot of work being put in to support seamless syncing with Apple iPods
and includes its own GStreamer mp3 encoder for instance to acomplish
this. Doesn't yet support the DAAP music sharing like Rhythmbox does for
instance, but if iPod support is what you want then this is definetly
the application to look out for. Banshee is licensed under a MIT style
license. You can find out more on the Banshee homepage:

http://www.banshee-project.org/index.php/Main_Page


Well that's all for this week. Thanks to Thomas, Luca, and Christian for
their contributions to this week's edition, and if you want to write
something for next week, send it along to me, preferably before Monday.

Until next time,
-- 
Andy Wingo
http://wingolog.org/
</pre>
</content>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>GStreamer status, 28 Sept 2005</title>
    <date>2005-09-28 12:48</date>
    <content>
<pre>
Hey folks,

It's a marvelous mercredi we have here, and a nice time for the second
edition of the GStreamer status report. So prop up your feet, grab a
GStreamer-approved beverage and relax as we go over the crucial
happenings of the last week.


The Bleeding Edge
-----------------

Stefan Kost is the hero of the week, for completely inlining all of
GStreamer's API documentation into the source code. Now the primary
source for all of the API documentation is maintained right beside the
API itself, which should help to increase the long-term quality of our
documentation. Go Stefan!

Interestingly enough, there were no actual API changes this week, as far
as I can tell -- just function additions, and moving around header files
as part of the documentation work. Added API includes structure field
and GstValue accessors for GstClockTime and GDate. Also,
gst_object_has_ancestor was made public, and fdsrc was ported and moved
to the core.

As an internal detail, Wim rewrote the state change algorithm this week.
Changing the states of a bin's children is a tricky operation in 0.9,
because changing state can cause elements to start pushing or pulling
data in another thread. Obviously this can only work if the other
elements in a bin are in the correct state to start processing when the
thread starts. The problem of determining the order in which the
element's states should be changed is complicated by allowing element
additions and removals from other threads while performing the state
change.

Wim solved this gracefully by implementing a GstIterator that iterates a
bin's children in state-change order, having done a topological sort,
and then folding over that iterator. Wow. I guess there's a reason we
keep him around.

Also, one of our primary data structures is acquiring a dependency on an
outside library. Congratulations to Jan Schmidt (thaytan)'s marriage to
Jaime Hemmett!


Meanwhile, Back At The Ranch
----------------------------

The "base" plugin set saw the normal set of bugfixes, some work on the
RTP payloader base class, seeking optimization work in playbin, and
general refactoring in sinesrc, the tcp elements, and audio sink base
classes.

News from the "good" plugins includes Tim Müller's fixing of OSS
playback of mono streams, fixes when demuxing AVI files containing
unknown types, refactoring in the level element by Thomas, porting of
auparse from 0.8 by Edgard Lima, and the normal batch of RTP work from
Wim.

In the "ugly" set, there were bugfixes in mp3parse and amrnbenc, and
Michael Smith wielded a sword of righteousness over the AC3 framer for
S/PDIF output.

Finally, the ttaparse and gsmdec plugins were ported to 0.9 by Arwed v.
Merkatz and Edgard Lima, respectively.


The Path To Release
-------------------

Andy Wingo proposed a tentative schedule[1] for GStreamer development
releases, culminating with 0.10.0 on 5 December. As part of that plan,
expect to see a 0.9.3 release of GStreamer and plugin modules on Monday
3 October. See the mail for more details.

[1] http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.video.gstreamer.devel/13768


Bugs
----

Total number of GStreamer bugs as of today : 206
Number opened in the last week             : +18
Number closed in the last week             : -23
Net change                                 : -5

GStreamer is currently number 8 on the list of projects with the most
bugs in GNOME bugzilla, which is one place higher than we were last
week.

On the 0.8 side of things, Luca Ognibene has been doing some great
work dealing with bugs. He could use a bit of help now, though -- check
out his recent mail to the list[2] for ways you can help.

[2] http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.video.gstreamer.devel/13808


Featured Application: Istanbul
------------------------------

Christian Schaller once again brings us this week's featured
application.

    Istanbul is a nice GStreamer based application made by Zaheer
    Merali. It gives you a small notification area icon which by a click
    of your mouse lets you stop or start recording sessions of your
    desktop. The resulting video is stored as an Ogg file. This is a
    quick and easy way to to create desktop videos demonstrating your
    favourite desktop application feature. And its all free software and
    using free media formats. You find more on Istanbul here:

    http://live.gnome.org/Istanbul

Thanks, Christian!


Well, that's about all for this week. Happy hacking!
</pre>
</content>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>GStreamer status, 05 October 2005</title>
    <date>2005-10-05 00:00</date>
    <content>
<p>
Mwa lala po oohacker yoGStreamer,
</p>

<p>
It's that time of the week again, where we take a caffeine-assisted look
at last week's events in GStreamer. So whether you percolate, filter,
steep or express, fill your mug and prepare to be educated.
</p>

<h3>Release, Release, Release, Release, Release, Release, Release</h3>

<p>Seven of them, my friends. Version 0.9.3 of GStreamer core,
plugins-base, -good, -bad, -ugly, ffmpeg, and gst-python were released
on Monday by Master Builder Thomas Vander Stichele (+47 endurance).
Check the main page[0] for links, and check the 0.10 roadmap[1] to see
how we're doing for the release. The next releases will be on 17
October, at which point the API will be frozen for four weeks. Any API
changes after 17 October will have to go through bugzilla, be reviewed,
and applied on 14 November. API stability for that time means 17 October
will be a great time to start porting your application to 0.9.
</p>


<p>[0] http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/<br/>
[1] http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.video.gstreamer.devel/13768
</p>

<h3>Core Happenings</h3>

<p>GStreamer is an abnormal GObject-based library in that it is
multithreaded. Because GTK+ is normally programmed from one thread,
programmers are not accustomed to having to think about concurrency. To
make application programming simpler, GStreamer 0.9 offers the ability
to marshal messages from the pipeline into the main thread.
</p>

<p>GStreamer does this by the use of a bus, where messages are received,
handled synchronously, and then depending on the return value of the
synchronous handler they can be placed on a threadsafe queue. There is
GLib integration that creates a GSource to operate in the main context,
so you can handle messages from this queue in your main loop.
Integration with other main loop APIs is also possible.
</p>

<p>Last week Wim Taymans made it even easier to use the bus. Now the
suggested way to use the bus is to connect to signals on the bus instead
of installing a bus watch. To listen for all messages, you connect to
the "message" signal. To listen for only EOS messages, you can connect
to "message::eos" (using the "detailed signal" functionality in GLib).
To use these signals, you will have to first call
gst_bus_add_signal_watch(), to add the bus integration to the main loop,
and gst_bus_remove_signal_watch() to clean up.
</p>

<p>You also have to option to receive signals synchronously via the
"sync-message" signal, but most programmers will find the "message"
signal to be more convenient.
</p>

<p>Other core changes include the normal bug fixes, refcount fixes in tee,
and the destruction of a couple of race conditions that affected mp3
playback.
</p>

<h3>Plugin Activity</h3>

<p>Cutting to the quick, a brief look at activity by module:
</p>

<ul>
<li>base: more robust error handling in ogg, theora, vorbis; cleanup fixes</li>
<li>good: rtp payloading bugfixes, enable tag reading in flacdec, flacenc
        ported to 0.9, cleanup fixes, dv query fixes</li>
<li>bad: qtdemux locking fix</li>
<li>  ugly: elite real demuxer work by Michael Smith</li>
</ul>

<p>FFMpeg also has gotten some love these days from Thomas and Wim.
</p>

<h3>Bug Status</h3>

<center>
<table width="50%">
<tr><td>Total number of GStreamer bugs as of today</td><td>207</td></tr>
<tr><td>Number opened in the last week</td><td>+13</td></tr>
<tr><td>Number closed in the last week</td><td>-23</td></tr>
<tr><td>Net change</td><td>-10</td></tr>
</table>
</center>

<p>We are again #9 in the GNOME bug rankings. Frankly though I don't see
how these numbers add up -- we were at 207 bugs last week. Does this
prove the existence of a divine being? Stay tuned next week to find out.
</p>

<h3>Current Releases</h3>

<p>Thomas considers it crucial that each and every one of you tatoo this
information to your forearms.</p>

<h4>Latest development versions</h4>
<center>
<table width="50%">
<tr><td>gstreamer</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-plugins-base</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-plugins-good</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-plugins-bad</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-plugins-ugly</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-ffmpeg</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-python</td><td>0.9.3</td></tr>
</table>
</center>

<h4>Latest stable versions</h4>
<center>
<table width="50%">
<tr><td>gstreamer</td><td>0.8.11</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-plugins</td><td>0.8.11</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-ffmpeg</td><td>0.8.6</td></tr>
<tr><td>gst-python</td><td>0.8.2</td></tr>
</table>
</center>

<h3>Featured Application: Thoggen</h3>

<p>Christian Schaller lets us know how to back up DVDs with GStreamer.
</p>

<blockquote>
    Looking for a tool to backup your DVD's? Well you are in luck. This
    week we take a look at Thoggen, written by Tim Müller, which gives
    you a nice looking GTK+ GUI for ripping your DVD's into Ogg files.
    It uses HAL/d-bus for DVD detection and provides nice features such
    as preview, picture cropping and picture resizing. So free yourself
    from DivX and move into the world of Ogg.
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
    You find Thoggen and lots of screenshots on the Thoggen website,
    http://thoggen.net/.
</blockquote>

<p>
Well well, there went another week and this status newsletter is all we
have to show for it, that and some code and tarballs and stuff. I'm now
syndicating this newsletter over RSS at
http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/news/status-rss-1.0.xml, for the more
technologically inclined out there. However it is you read, farewell for
another half-fortnight. Tu hackeni nenyanyu (Happy hacking).
</p>
</content>
  </item>
</status>
